Driver's name is Arthur Shea.
司機的名字是阿瑟席亞
Former Medford police officer 57 years old.
前密德福市警察，5 7歲
Soon as his partner leaves with the coal bag...
他的同夥一把帆布袋拿走
...Artie cracks The Herald, and he don't look up till the guy gets back.
阿瑟就假裝看報，等他上車
Marty MacGuire, Cummins Armored courier:
馬提麥奎爾，運鈔車警衛
5'10" 220, 52 years old.
五英尺十英吋，兩百二十磅，5 2歲
Picks up every Wednesday and Friday at exactly 8:12.
每週三和五準時8點1 2分取錢
Makes $110 a day. Carries a SIG 9.
日薪110美元
And he's about to get robbed.
他即將被搶劫
We're fucked if we see a helicopter, we're fucked if we see SWAT.
看到直升機或反恐特警組就死定了
We see a cruiser, stop, take out the engine blocks, keep moving.
看到警車就射爛引擎繼續往前開
No one needs to get hurt.
沒有人需要受傷
Now, these guards like to test you, though.
那些警衛喜歡向你挑釁
They want to get hurt for $10 an hour, don't get in the way.
時薪十元的他們想挨子彈 就向他們開槍
Let's go.
上吧
Move!
快、快！
All right, now getaway from the counter!
給我離開櫃檯！
Go! Go! Go! Everybody away!
快！滾開！退到牆邊！
You! Away from the computer!
你！離電腦遠一點！
-Give me the fucking key! -Back up! Back! Go! Go!
把鑰匙給我！
-Get up! Get up! -Get the fucking door!
-起來！快點！ -趴下來！趴下來！
Get on the ground!
趴在地上！
-Get down on the ground. -Get your fucking ass on the ground!
-給我趴在地上！ -給我乖乖趴在地上！
Move! Go, go, go, go!
快點！快點！
-On the floor! -I need everybody's BlackBerrys.
-趴下來！ -我要大家的黑莓手機
-Everybody on the floor. -Slide your BlackBerrys up.
-趴下來 -把黑莓手機丟到前面
Take off your fucking shoes!
把鞋子脫下來！
BlackBerrys to the front! Slide your fucking phones up.
把黑莓手機丟到前面！快點！
-The fuck you looking at? -Take your shoes off.
-看什麼看？ -把鞋子脫掉
-Take off your fucking shoes! -Take off your shoes.
-快給我把鞋子脫掉！ -把鞋子脫掉
Bank manager, let's go. Get up. Let's go.
銀行經理，起來，走吧
Get up, come on, get up. Let's go.
起來，快走！
Not you. You. Get up. Let's go. Come on.
不是你 你，起來，走吧
-You trying to be a hero? -Jesus Christ!
-你想逞英雄嗎？ -老天爺！
-When's the time lock set for? -09:00.
時間鎖幾點失效？
Don't lie to us, it's 8:15.
-9點 -別想騙我們，是8點15分
Listen, it's not your money. You understand? Don't lie to us again.
這不是你的錢，瞭解嗎？
Hey, sweetheart, in the corner. Get in the corner. You too, brother-man.
小妞，到角落去
Go. Go.
快，快
No distress call. Open it clean.
不准啟動警鈴，乖乖開鎖
-I'm sorry, I'm sorry. I'm sorry. -Don't stall,
-天啊，對不起 -別拖延時間
This guy a fucking friend of yours?
這傢伙是你朋友嗎？
Let's go!
快點！
I'm sorry, I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
對不起…對不起…
Take your time, okay?
慢慢來
Breathe. Go.
深呼吸，開始
Okay, get back. Get out of the way.
退後！讓開！
Front door.
前門
-Hello. -Front door.
-喂？ -前門！
Hey, you guys open?
你們有營業嗎？
We gotta go.
我們得閃了
Let's go. Let's bleach it up.
走吧！潑漂白水！
-Go, go, go. -Let's bleach it up.
-我們得閃了 -快走，潑漂白水
-Come on, let's go. We gotta go. -Hold it. Silent alarm, this address.
快，得閃了
-Who did it? -Look, nobody did anything.
-是誰幹的？ -沒有人
-What? Huh? What'd you say? -Nobody did anything.
你說什麼？
-You pull the alarm? -No. No.
-是你按的？ -不，不
-Did you? -I didn't pull any alarm.
-是你嗎？ -我沒按警鈴
We were leaving, you motherfucker! You fuck!
我們正要走了，狗娘養的
Easy, easy. That's enough.
冷靜點，夠了
-All right? Easy. -You fuck!
-夠了啦 -我們就要走了，你這混蛋！
Let's go.
走吧
Where's your purse?
你的皮包呢？
What the fuck is this?
你在幹嘛？
The cops get us walled in, we're gonna need her.
警察來了，我們需要她
Sit down. Go.
坐下來
Head for the boulevard.
走那條路
You're gonna be okay.
你不會有事的，好吧 沒人會傷害你
What's up?
什麼情況？
Boosted a city work van. Which still hasn't been reported stolen.
搶匪偷走一輛公家廂型車 還沒有報失
Probably too busy working.
他們大概在忙吧
Used the van to screen the door.
搶匪用廂型車擋住大門
Bleached the entire place for DNA.
潑漂白水以免DNA被查到
Kills all the clothing fiber, so we can't get a match.
也沒留下衣物纖維
Silent bell came from cage number two.
無聲警鈴來自二號櫃檯
Assistant manager's at Beth Israel.
助理經理在醫院
Our guys waited for the time lock to expire...
搶匪等到時間鎖失效
...then they had the manager open sesame.
然後讓經理開鎖
Under duress?
被脅迫的嗎？
I don't know.
我不知道
Ten foot steel safe.
十英尺厚的鋼門
Only as strong as the guy with the key.
只要有鑰匙就能打開
Found the dye packs and the tracers.
搶匪找到裝有追蹤器的鈔票
Found the van, Torched.
找到廂型車，全被燒燬
-Where is it? -Where do you think?
在哪堙H
-Nice to be back home, Dino? -Yeah.
-回家的感覺好吧，迪諾？ -還好
It's all the love I get makes the homecoming feel so warm.
是我得到的愛 才使回家的感覺如此溫暖
Could be 50 people here eyewitnessed these guys.
可能有50個人看到了他們
And 50 hands on a bible saying they never saw nothing.
然而這50個人卻會發誓 他們什麼都沒看到
Well, it's a pro job.
這是高手所為
All the pro guys I know are away...
我知道的高手都離開了
...so I guess we got new pro guys.
所以我想新的高手出現了
The part of the job where we get to do something...
我們的職責之一是要做一些
...that has no point and yields no results. Excuse me.
毫無意義也毫無結果的事 請問一下
Anybody see who lit this van on fire?
有誰看到是誰點著這台麵包車嗎？
Is that where we are now?
我們現在要這麼搞嗎？
Where's Jem?
小詹呢？
Stopped on the way to light a couple house tires...
也許正在順路燒幾棟房子
...stick up a liquor store, maybe, I don't know.
搶幾家雜貨店，我不知道
-Are we taking hostages now? -No, we're not taking hostages now.
-我們要開始挾持人質嗎？ -不，沒有
-You gonna talk to this fucking asshole? -For one thing--
你要跟那個小王八蛋說嗎？
Hey.
嘿
Speak of the fucking devil.
說曹操曹操就到
You made it.
你終於來了
-Take the scenic route? -We got a problem.
-去兜風嗎？ -有件麻煩事
-What? -Well, look.
什麼事？
So what?
又怎樣？
What's the matter? Let me see that.
搞什麼？給我看
Fuck. Oh, shit.
該死
-See the address on that? -Bitch lives four blocks away.
-有看到住址嗎？ -這賤貨住在四個街口外
Yeah, I know where we are, Gloans. Fuck.
我知道還用你說嗎，葛隆，該死！
We gonna see this bitch on the street every day?
-該死！ -咱們每天都會撞見她？
She didn't see anything.
她什麼也沒看到
Jesus, are you sure?
你確定？
-Taking her for a ride didn't help. -Yeah.
-你不該把她帶上車的 -對
Oh, fuck. All right. I'm gonna handle it.
該死，我會搞定的
How you gonna handle this?
你要怎麼搞定？
I'm gonna stalk her like a fucking A car, we'll find out.
我要跟蹤她，把事情搞清楚
-Find out what? -If she needs to get scared.
-搞清楚什麼事？ -我們需不需要嚇唬她
-She's already scared. -Well, maybe not scared enough.
-她已經被嚇壞了 -也許還不夠
Thanks, Kathy.
謝了，凱西
Ms. Keesey. Special Agent Adam Frawley, Violent Crimes and Robbery.
基席小姐，暴力犯罪搶案組
Derek here is gonna take some elimination prints.
戴瑞克需要你的指紋
I see you've given a preliminary statement.
你已經做了初步供詞
I want to talk to you about your abduction.
但我想談談你被挾持的經過
Okay.
好吧
-I understand they threatened you. -Mm-hm.
聽說他們威脅你
One of them took my license.
其中一個拿走我的駕照
And did you try to escape at any point?
你有試圖逃走嗎？
No.
沒有
Is there anything you can identify about the men? Anything you'd testify to?
你能指認這些搶匪嗎？ 或是有任何線索？
I didn't try to escape because they had guns.
他們有槍，我不敢逃
I understand.
我瞭解
Then they just let you go?
然後他們就放你走？
-Yeah. They just let me go. -Thanks.
-對，他們就放我走 -謝謝
When someone endures an experience like this...
當一個人有過這種經歷
...there are very often residual effects.
通常會有後遺癥
It's gonna be okay.
但你不會有事
Did they say anything?
他們有說什麼嗎？
"if you talk to the FBI, we'll come to your house and fuck you and kill you."
「你敢和FBI合作
Are you gonna take care of it?
你要去搞定？
-I'll do it. -Why are you gonna do it?
-我去 -為什麼你去？
You're the reason we're having this conversation.
-因為這是你惹的麻煩
-I'm gonna get it done. -What are you gonna get done? Huh?
我會搞定的
You get picked up for intimidating a witness.
你會因威脅證人被捕
You walk within 100 feet of her, that's 10 years. Okay?
接近她1 0 0英尺會被關1 0年
You got two strikes against you already. They're gonna bury you under the jail.
你被關過兩次，再進去就出不來了
How much money's in the sack?
袋子埵釵h少錢？
All right, we got 90 a pop.
每人分九萬
Minus what I had to shave off for the Florist.
減掉要給花店老闆的錢
Hey, Jem, what happened with the assistant manager?
小詹，你幹嘛痛扁助理經理？
Yeah. Well, next time Skeletor comes in the bank with an AK...
下次骷髏王拿衝鋒鎗闖進銀行
...I think he's gonna think twice about hitting that alarm, isn't he?
他就不敢再按無聲警鈴了
He's lucky he just got tuned up.
我只扁他算他幸運
Are you gonna catch them?
你們會抓住他們嗎？
Yes.
會的
This is the FBI. We're not completely inept.
這堿O聯邦調查局 我們並非一無是處
In fact...
實際上
...I know where they are.
我知道他們在哪
Three hundred and seventy bank robberies in Boston last year.
去年波士頓發生了 370宗銀行搶劫案
More per capita than anywhere else in the world.
案發率比世界上任何地方都要高
The guys like this, hardcore guys, pros, 90 percent of them...
像這樣兇狠專業的傢伙百分之九十
...emanate from a one-square-mile neighborhood called Charlestown.
都來自一個一平方英里的地區 它叫查爾斯敦
-Familiar with it? -You must be kidding me.
-熟悉嗎？ -開玩笑吧
First thing B.P.D. does when there's an armored-car robbery?
當發生運鈔車搶劫案的時候 警局做的第一件事是什麼？
-Close the Charlestown Bridge. -And he's from Charlestown.
-封鎖查爾斯敦大橋 -他來自查爾斯敦
They use each other's yards, houses. They're like rats.
他們使用彼此的後院，房屋 他們就像老鼠
They ditch us pretty quick.
他們很快就能甩掉我們
Heisting banks is a trade in Charlestown.
打劫銀行在查爾斯敦是一個行業
The way villages in old Europe used to be known for certain crafts.
舊歐洲的村莊以某種手工藝出名
In the town, it's banks and armored cars.
在這個鎮 它以銀行以運鈔車出名
I don't understand it, but it makes it easier when you know which bridge to close.
我不明白其中道理，但是知道 該封鎖哪座橋會使事情更好辦
Quinlan will set you up with a detail.
昆蘭探員會告訴你細節
Meantime, if there's anything your witness specialist can't do for you ....
同時，如果有什麼事情 你的目擊者專家無法做到
You got nothing to worry about. We're gonna find these guys.
沒什麼好擔心的 我們會找到那些傢伙
-Hi, how you doing? -Good. How are you?
-你好嗎？ -很好，你呢？
-Good. Come in. -Nice to see you.
-很好，進來吧 -很高興見到你
-Good to see you. -How have you been?
-近來怎麼樣？
-Good. Come in and have a seat. -Thanks, Margie.
-很好，進來坐坐吧 -謝謝，瑪吉
-Can I get you guys anything? -We're fine. Thank you.
-要喝點什麼嗎？ -不用了，謝謝
-Okay, well, Mike'll be right out. -Terrific.
-好的，麥克很快就出來 -好極了
Really done well for himself.
他自己過得還真不賴
Yeah.
沒錯
He got good money for that place in the town.
鎮堛漕滬茼a方他賣了不少錢
Why does anybody move to Saugus?
為什麼會有人搬去索格斯？
It's gonna take us an hour to get over the Portagee Slide.
翻過波特吉斜坡要一個小時
Yep.
沒錯
Jesus.
天啊
This shit with the Florist is getting old, man.
買花的生意就要過時了，夥計
I'm investing in a marquee score.
我要投資一家帳篷店
All right? So we gotta make a few payments.
好嗎？所以我們要給他一些錢
Fuck making payments to him.
去他媽的給錢
Hey, let me give you some advice.
我給你一些建議
Money don't care where it came from, all right?
有錢就行，不用在乎來路 好嗎？
The guy's a fucking Lucky Charms Irishman...
這傢伙是個幸運的愛爾蘭人
...who can't find no one to sell his AKs to...
他找不到買家買他的武器
...so he's selling narcotics, trying to be the boss.
所以也改賣毒品，他想做老大
You didn't seem to care when you were dropping 2 grand a week...
當你每個星期都花兩千美元
...on Monsters and Yay, did you?
逍遙快樂時你好像並不在乎 是嗎？
Look, there's a difference between a dealer and a straight killer, all right?
聽著，毒販和殺手是不同的
So he dropped a few Dominicans. What, are you picky?
所以他甩掉了幾個多米尼加人 你還想怎樣？
Hey, guys.
夥計們
-Hey, Mike.
-麥克
-Here you go, guys. -Hey.
-都在這堣F，夥計們 -嘿
Here you go.
拿著|
-Hundred G's? -That's right.
-十萬美元？ -沒錯
Look at this.
看看這個
-Like a newborn baby. All right. -That's it.
-真不錯，好的 -沒錯
-Take care, guys. -All right. Good to see you, Mike.
-保重，夥計們 -好的，很高興見到你，麥克
-Looking good. -All right.
-好極了 -好了
-Hundred pounds. -Hundred grand.
-一百磅 -十萬美元
There you go.
看看吧
-Green money. -All right.
-美鈔 -好的
-Be smart, brother. We'll see you. -Thanks. Thank you.
-祝你順利，兄弟，再見 -謝謝
-Hey, Rusty. How you doing? -Hey, Jem. What's up? How are you?
-洛帝，你好嗎？ -小詹，怎麼樣？
Fergie. Kid's here.
付老大，臭小子們來了
Hey, Fergie.
付老大
-Here you go. -How's it going, son?
-拿去 -你還好吧？
All right. You run that under the sink, all right?
還好
Trust me.
放心
All right. Good to see you.
好吧，見到你真好
Take it easy, man. Good to see you.
保重了，老兄
Now it's time for the fun part.
玩樂時間到了
What's going on, pal?
怎麼樣，老兄？
What up?
怎麼樣？
Hey, there he is.
他來了
-Boom. -Sober Jackson.
不喝酒的男人
-What's up? -Hey, hey. Krista's here.
-怎麼樣？ -克莉絲也來了
Go on, tell the story.
來呀，告訴他呀
Dougy, sit down. I'm trying to tell these motherfuckers about your father.
道格，坐，我正聊到你老爸
The Feds will never understand the guy who's facing 40 years,
聯邦探員搞不懂，他被判4 0年
Gonna give him the opportunity to walk soot-free if he gives up his friends.
只要招出同夥就能拍屁股走人
He tells them, "Suck a dick. Give me the 40."
他卻說：「吃屎吧，我要關4 0年」
"Fucking suck a dick."
說的好
Yeah, well, here's to Big Mac.
敬大麥
Doing his time like a man.
-像個男子漢蹲苦窯 -沒錯
-That's right. -Last crew in Charlestown.
咱們是最上道的搶匪
I'm gonna get a tonic, I guess.
我要去點杯蘇打水
All right. Get me an umbrella for my beer.
替我要一支裝飾小雨傘
Let me get a Shirley Temple with an extra cherry, please.
替我點一杯雪莉登波
-Thanks. -No problem.
-謝了 -不客氣
Juice?
果汁？
Yeah. Juice.
對，果汁
Do you want some snappers to go with that?
要加點料嗎？
Fuck.
該死
My drink.
我的飲料
Heard you got in a tight, Kris.
聽說你打了一架
Do I look like I got in a fight?
我看起來像嗎？
I don't know. Let me see. They pull your hoop out?
不知道，耳環被扯掉嗎？
That's right.
沒錯
The Jamaican started it.
這是那些牙買加人發起的
"The Jamaican started it." What Jamaican?
什麼牙買加人？
Fucking Somalian started talking shit when I was with my daughter.
臭黑婆娘在我和女兒面前亂罵
You were with Shyne?
你和小珊在一起？
Tonya was with us. And Cheryl too.
還有棠雅和謝麗兒
-The other girl was by herself? -Yeah.
-另一個女孩是單獨的？ -是的
All they see are yuppies down here.
她們見到的都是雅皮士
They think there's no more serious white people in Charlestown.
查爾斯敦沒有正經的白人
So they can fucking talk shit? No.
這樣他們就可以亂說話？不行
You didn't say nothing to her first?
你不先跟她打個招呼？
I said something after I slapped the black off her face.
我扇了她耳光之後跟她說了一些話
-Right, yeah. -Fuck.
-好吧 -去他的
Well, do you miss it?
你懷念嗎？
Fucking coke and Oxy and all that shit? Yeah, I miss it.
可卡因和K他命？我好懷念
You know what I miss?
你知道我懷念什麼嗎？
The fucking grip I used to get on your armrest.
我以前在你的躺椅上找到的毒品
We smoked it to the filter, right?
我們以前嗑藥嗑到爽翻天
-So have one beer. -Jimmy.
-喝瓶啤酒吧 -吉米
-One beer ain't gonna kill you, right? -Drink my beer for me real quick.
-喝瓶啤酒死不了，對嗎？ -幫我把酒喝掉
-And one for me. -One for you? Yeah.
-拿支給我 -拿支給你？好的
Dougy.
道格
Motherfucker, I know you can hear me.
混蛋，我知道你聽到了
You know I got a key, Dougy.
你知道我有鑰匙
Come on in.
進來吧
Too fucking busy, huh?
很忙嗎？
Come on, Dougy.
來吧，道格
What's up, Kris?
什麼事，克莉絲？
There you go.
看看吧
That's what you want, right?
這是你要的，對吧？
-Yeah. -Is that what you want?
-對 -這是你要的嗎？
Say you love it.
說你喜歡這樣
Good night.
晚安
I'm grateful to be here today.
我很高興今天能來這
I started out with alcohol, and, you know, right away...
我剛開始時喝酒，很快
...went to cocaine and smoking crack.
我就吸起了可卡因和古柯堿
Growing up in Charlestown in, you know, a small-knit community...
我在查爾斯敦長大
My friends were really like my family.
我的朋友就像是家人
I'm ashamed of the things I done when I'm out there.
我嗑藥時做過很丟臉的事
Seven years went by, and I'd watch Christmas, birthdays--
我有七年沒過聖誕節和生日
I didn't know what my son looked like.
連兒子都認不得
Make a fast buck if we had to...
有需要就去弄點錢
...that progressed into getting arrested, and ....
結果搞到被逮捕
The struggle that you have within yourself the loss, you know what I mean?
我的內心很痛苦、很空虛
It's like the guy sitting in the bar, and a priest walks in.
有個人坐在酒吧，神父走進來
The guy says, "Hey, wait a minute.
想坐他旁邊 他對神父說：「等一下
I hate to tell you this, don't waste your time, but I happen to know there's no God."
別浪費時間，我不相信有上帝」
The priest says, "Yeah, how's that?"
神父說：「你怎麼知道？」
The guy says, "I was an explorer in the North Pole.
他說：「我曾是北極探險家
I got caught in a blinding storm once. Freezing. I was blinded.
遇到暴風雪，什麼都看不見
Freezing to death. And I prayed, 'If there's a God, save me now'
就快冷死，於是我祈求上帝救我
Now, God didn't come."
上帝並沒有來」
And the priest says, you know, "How's that? You're alive. He must've saved you."
神父說：「你怎麼知道？」
An Eskimo came along, took me back to his camp and saved me."
卻來個愛斯基摩人
That's Janice. She's my wife and she's sitting right there.
那是我老婆珍妮絲，就在那
She's my Eskimo.
她是我的愛斯基摩人
-How you doing? -Hey.
-你好嗎？ -很好
Excuse me?
不好意思，你在洗衣服嗎？
-Can't help you. Sorry. -Okay.
-沒有，抱歉 -沒關係
I can just hang them up when I get home.
我可以拿回家晾乾
You all right?
你還好吧？
I'm fine. I'm just--
還好，只是…
Are you sure?
你確定？
You okay?
你沒事吧？
Yeah, I'm fine. I'm fine, thank you. I'm fine, yeah.
沒事，我很好，謝謝你
Well, this is embarrassing.
好丟臉哦
No, you got nothing to be embarrassed for.
沒什麼好丟臉的
Do you need help?
你需要幫忙嗎？
I'm just having a bad week.
這禮拜很不順
I understand.
我瞭解
I like to have a good cry at the nail salon.
我喜歡到彩繪指甲店大哭一場
Just open right up to the ladies. They're very understanding.
向店堛漱p姐大吐苦水
But, you know, you like the Laundromat, so that's fine.
不過你愛在自助洗衣店哭也行
Hey, why don't you let me buy you a drink.
不如讓我請你喝一杯
Make up for letting you down with the quarters.
彌補我沒有零錢給你換的錯
You know, see if we can turn your week around.
也許能讓你好過一些
What's the worst that could happen?
沒什麼不好的對吧？
FBI! Open the door
聯邦調查局，把門打開
Open the door!
把門打開！
Fuck.
該死
Fucking cocksucker. Get off him.
混蛋！放開他！
Jesus Christ, Henry.
真是的，亨利
Oxy, guns?
K他命、槍？
It's like townie Christmas.
簡直就像過聖誕節
Minimum federal sentencing, 10 years.
最輕的刑期是十年
You're gonna need a friend.
你需要一個朋友
And she ain't it.
並不是她
Great girl, though. She really loves you, I can tell.
她是好女孩，看得出她很愛你
Good news for you is you have an alibi for the Cambridge job.
好消息是 劍橋市搶案你有不在場證明
The good news for me is I bet you know something about it.
但我知道你一定知道什麼
Everyone does trucks.
大家都搶運鈔車
These guys beat the alarm for the vault.
那些傢伙直接搶銀行金庫
-Yeah? -It's what I heard.
-是嗎？ -我聽說的
A kid, he gets into the junction box.
有個小子破壞了警報器
-This is nice. -Yeah, it's a good place.
-這很不錯 -是的，這是個好地方
A guy I played hockey with for a long time is one of the managers here.
一個和我打了很長時間曲棍球的人 是這堛漱@個經理
Oh, yeah? That's nice.
是嗎？太好了
So, what do you do for work?
你在哪堣u作？
Boston Sand and Gravel.
波士頓砂石公司
...slide down the back of a brontosaurus like Fred Flintstone.
像摩登原始人滑下雷龍的背
Call it a night.
然後回家休息
-Can I ask you something? -You sure can.
-我能問個問題嗎？ -當然能
I volunteer at the Boys & Girls Club in Charlestown--
我是查爾斯敦兒童俱樂部志工
-Oh, yeah? -Yeah.
-是嗎？ -是啊
As a kickball pitcher since they haven't been able to afford any ice for the rink.
我通常只是去丟丟球
Embarrassing, City won't put any money into that place.
真的很丟臉，市政府不肯出錢
Yeah, I know. Yeah, well, some of the kids were calling me a toonie?
沒錯，有些孩子會叫我「突尼」
It just means a yuppie. Someone who's not from Charlestown, that's all.
意思是來自查爾斯敦以外的雅痞
-Of course it does. -They're just being punks.
原來如此
-A yuppie. -Yeah.
-一個雅皮士 -是的
-So where does the word come from? -Uh ....
這個詞是什麼時候出現的？
It comes from back in the '90s, like...
它出現於九十年代
...the toonies supplied all the tunes to Charlestown."
那些「突尼」 給查爾斯敦帶來了音樂
...because once they moved in the townies stole all their car stereos.
因為當他們搬進城堳 城堣H把他們汽車堛滬腋T都偷了
So all of a sudden, everyone in Charlestown...
所以，突然間 查爾斯敦所有的車
...had a Blaupunkt in their car, you know what I mean?
都安上了德國藍寶牌音響 明白我的意思嗎？
Anyway.
話說回來
So do your parents still live in Charlestown?
你的雙親還住在查爾斯敦嗎？
No. My mother moved away.
沒有，我母親搬走了
My father lives out in the suburbs.
我父親住在郊區
Yeah. He don't get out much.
是的，他不經常出去
-No, I mean where did you grow up? -Marblehead.
-不，我是說你是在哪堛齯j的？ -馬波赫
Marblehead?
馬波赫？
Yeah, well, I represent Marblehead's poor.
是的，我代表馬波赫的窮人
-Oh, really? -Yeah, you were defined by...
-真的嗎？ -是的，你的身份
...whether or not your family owned a boat. And, well, my family didn't own a boat.
由你的家庭是否擁有一艘遊艇決定 我家沒有…
No boat. How could you look yourself in the mirror?
沒有遊艇，你不會感到自卑嗎？
It's embarrassing.
太令人尷尬了
-I have a boat. -Oh, yeah?
-我有一艘遊艇 -是嗎？
-Yeah. -Well, you would do well in Marblehead.
-是的 -如果你在馬波赫應該會不錯
Yeah, maybe. It's not my boat, it's my friend's boat.
也許吧，不是我的遊艇，是我朋友的
You should...
你應該…
...let me take you for a ride sometime.
找個時間和我乘船出遊
-I'd love that. Sometime. -Yeah.
-我很樂意，等有時間吧 -好的
What about right now?
現在怎麼樣？
That's the boat. Right there.
就是那艘，那
-Not bad, right? -Good friends to have.
-還不錯吧？ -這樣的朋友不錯
Here you go. It's the best cup I could find.
拿著，這是我能找到的最好的杯子
Not too much.
別喝太多
Thank you.
謝謝
It's nice, right? I told you.
很不錯，對吧？我早說了
Is this where you take all the girls?
你和女孩約會都來這媔隉H
I can honestly tell you I have never taken another girl here in my entire life.
老實說，我一生中 還沒帶過另一個女孩來這
-Oh, yeah? -Mm-hm. That's the truth.
-是嗎？ -這是真的
Hey, what do you know about bank robbers?
你對銀行搶劫犯有什麼瞭解？
-What's to know? -You're from Charlestown.
-有什麼好瞭解的？ -你來自查爾斯敦
I figured you grew up with some of them.
我以為你和他們當中的一些人長大
No, not really. I mean ....
不，沒有，我是說…
A lot of what they say is exaggerated. I mean, I--
他們說的很多東西都言過其辭 我是說，我…
When I was a kid, uh...
當我還小的時候
...we used to go to Wizard's ice cream.
我們會去威查德冰淇淋店
It was across from J.J.'s Bar.
它在傑傑酒吧對面
That was where all the big armored-car guys hung out.
那些開運鈔車的人 就在那堨斯o時間
And they were like rock stars in the neighborhood, you know?
他們在附近地區就像搖滾明星
Fancy cars. Pretty girls.
漂亮的車，漂亮的女孩
And you heard rumors about the jobs they pulled.
你會聽說他們所犯的事
The big houses they had in Holbrook or Winthrop.
他們在霍爾布魯克和溫索普鎮 擁有大大的房子
There was a lot of kids in the ice-cream shop...
冰淇淋店埵釩雃h小孩
...with their noses pressed against the glass, you know...
他們把臉貼在玻璃上往堿
...who wanted to be like those guys.
他們想像那些傢伙一樣
I just wanted to play hockey.
而我只是想玩曲棍球
Anyway, that's what I know about bank robbers.
我對銀行搶劫犯的瞭解就那麼多
-Hey, Jem. How's it going? -Hey, B. Can I have a beer? Thanks.
小詹，你好
-Oh, shit. -What up?
-該死 -你好嗎？
What's going on?
-怎麼樣？ -沒怎樣？
You, uh, check on that thing?
你有去查嗎？
What?
什麼？
The license.
駕照呀
-Yeah. -And?
有
Nothing. It's a dead end, We're all set.
沒事，我們沒事
So no need to remove her from the equation?
所以不必把她除掉嘍？
-What? -You heard me.
什麼？
What are you, a triggerman now?
你變成殺手啦？
Just loose ends, kid.
只是不想留下證人
You're gonna get the fucking electric chair brought back over to Charlestown.
你會讓州政府恢復死刑
Don't be so goddamned panicked, all right, Dig Dug?
別這麼緊張嘛，道格
Just, you know, I don't wanna get backdoored, that's all.
我只是不想被害到
-We're fine. All right? -All right. We're fine.
我們沒事，好嗎？
They obviously know how to work the box.
他們顯然知道如何破壞警報器
But I like the way they zapped the BPT to the D-5 station.
他們也破壞D5分局的警報器
How does one learn how to do that?
要怎樣才能學會這招？
Get a job at Vericom.
到保安公司上班
-Okay. -Thank you.
-好吧 -謝謝你
All right, let's subpoena work logs, employee records.
調閱工作記錄和員工資料
Start with everybody who lives in the town.
先從住在查爾斯敦的員工查起
Go! it.
瞭解
Ms. Keesey, it's Agent Frawley. I have follow-up questions about your case.
基席小姐，我是弗勞利探員 關於你的案件我還有些問題要問你
Is there somewhere we can meet?
我們約個地方見面好嗎？
Why didn't you tell me you lived in Charlestown?
為什麼你不告訴我 你以前住在查爾斯敦？
It's on my paperwork.
它寫在我的文件上
You don't like your sandwich?
你不喜歡吃三明治？
It's the unfortunate nagging suspicion you get as an FBI agent..
作為一名聯邦探員 我沒辦法疑心不重
...who has put a lot of neighborhood people in federal prison...
我讓附近很多罪犯進了聯邦監獄
...that someone may have violated your meal.
也許有人會對我吃的東西動手腳
Come on, I don't think anyone would do that.
拜託，我覺得沒人會那樣做
They throw Tom Fitz off the roof of Mishawum for cooperating...
他們把湯姆費茲從密莎翁姆酒店 樓頂扔下，因為他與警方合作
...and then stand around and taunt him while he drowned in his own blood.
然後站在一旁嘲笑他 任由他浸在自己的血泊中
So I don't think the lunch special is out of bounds.
所以來一頓特色午餐也沒什麼出奇
Okay.
好吧
They lionize criminals...
他們崇拜罪犯
...and complain about crime...
卻又抗議犯罪
...and I'm the bad guy.
我卻成了壞人
This place is one square mile.
這個地方只有一平方英里
You walk into Lewisburg, there's a hundred townies in there.
你走進路易斯堡 堶探N有上百個居民
Well, I think I'll skip Lewisburg.
我不想談路易斯堡
Doesn't sound like a fun second date?
聽起來真是有趣的第二次約會
If I ask a question, will you give an honest answer?
如果我問一個問題 你會如實回答嗎？
It depends on the question.
那要看是什麼問題
Am I a suspect?
我是嫌犯嗎？
Would I ask you out if I thought you were a suspect?
如果我覺得你是嫌犯 我會約你出來嗎？
I don't know.
我不知道
-Would you? -Not if I wanted a conviction.
-你會嗎？ -如果我要定你的罪的話就不會
I might be seeing someone already.
我可能已經有約會對象了
-What? What is it? -Stickup.
-怎麼了？是什麼？ -搶劫
Chelsea Credit Union.
地點是切爾西信用社
What would we do without Chelsea?
沒有切爾西我們還有什麼事做？
Anyway, aren't there rules?
不過，對這些事不是有規定嗎？
Against dating the Vic? Yeah, there's a rule.
不准和受害者約會？ 沒錯，是有規定
You don't do it.
這是禁止的
-There she is. -Hey.
你出來了
-All set? -Yes,
準備好了嗎？
I should have come get your door for you, huh?
我應該下車替你開門
What kind of a guy lets you open your own door like that?
哪種男生會讓爾自己開門？
What?
什麼？
I have to get something out there...
我得先說一件事
...otherwise I'll be pretending to listen to you all night...
不然我會假裝聽你說話
...when really I'm thinking about something else.
其實心堣@直想著那件事
Okay.
好吧
A few days ago my bank was robbed.
前幾天我工作的銀行被搶
Four men took it over and opened the safe.
四名搶匪闖進去打開了金庫
They took me as a hostage.
他們挾持我當人質
They blindfolded me and drove me around.
蒙住我的眼睛，開車兜來兜去
And then they stopped and let me out over at the beach and ....
然後停在海邊讓我下車
And one of the guys told me...
其中一個叫我往前走
...to walk until I felt the water on my toes.
直到我的腳碰到水
It was the longest walk of my life. I kept thinking I'd step off a cliff.
那是我一生走過最長的路 我一直以為會掉下懸崖
And then I felt the water.
然後我就踩到了水
I'm sorry.
很抱歉
It's not your fault.
又不是你的錯
Anyway, the FBI guy told me it would feel like I was in mourning.
總之FBI探員說我會覺得很崩潰
FBI? You're working with the FBI?
FBI?你和FBI合作？
What does that mean?
那是什麼意思？
Guy comes by, checks in on you, gives you a call? That kind of thing?
有人會來看你或打電話給你？
Pretty much.
差不多吧
They don't have any suspects? Any clues? Any leads? Anything like that?
他們找到嫌犯或線索了嗎？
I don't know. Not that they've told me.
不知道，他們沒跟我說
He intimated that they were scouring Charlestown...
他說他們在查爾斯敦搜查
...but they were wearing masks, so....
不過搶匪戴了面具…
-Shit. -Mm.
可惡
I'm sure I'd recognize their voices if I heard them again.
我再聽到他們的聲音一定認得
I don't know, might be harder than you think.
不一定，可能比你想像的難
At least you weren't hurt.
還好你沒受傷
No.
是的
No, but David was.
我沒有，但是大衛受傷了
My assistant manager, he was assaulted really badly when the alarm went off.
我的經理助理 警報響起的時候他被痛打了一頓
He's been at Mass Eye and Ear for a week.
他已經在麻省眼耳中心住了一周
Eye surgery.
他做了眼部手術
And I still haven't been able to go see him.
我到現在都還不能去見他
I feel like a terrible person.
我覺得自己是個很糟糕的人
Then I guess we know where we're going.
那麼我想我們要去哪了
Well, you should come in.
你應該進來
-Yeah? -Yeah, you should meet him.
-是嗎？ -是的，你應該見見他
All right.
好吧
-Hi. -Hello. Hi.
-你好
Oh, hi. Come to my good side.
你好，到我沒出事的臉這邊
-Hi. -Look. You don't look so bad.
-聽著，情況看起來並不壞
-Really? -Well, you know.
-是嗎？ -是的
-Hello. -Hey.
-你好
-This is my friend Doug. -Hi. Nice to meet you.
-這是我的朋友道格 -你好，很高興見到你
Nice to meet you. I can almost see you.
很高興見到你 我差不多可以看清你的樣子了
So...
聽說
...they're hopeful.
他們覺得很有希望
Well, "hopeful" means I may recover...
有希望的意思是我可能會恢復
...50 percent of my sight in this eye.
這隻眼的五成視力
Oh, I just want to get back to work.
我真想回去工作
I'm gonna give you guys some privacy. I'll be right outside.
我讓你們倆私下談談，我到外面
-You heard what happened? -Huh?
你聽到發生什麼事了嗎？
Big takedown robbery.
大宗搶劫案
-Fucking punks laid the guy out. -Oh, yeah?
-那些混蛋打了他一頓 -是嗎？
It's a good thing you're here.
還好你在這
Those guys could come back.
那些傢伙可能會回來
Yeah.
對
I lied to the FBI.
我向聯邦探員說謊
What?
什麼？
When the guy attacked David...
那傢伙毆打大衛時
...I could see the back of his neck and he had a tattoo.
我看到他的後頸有個刺青
Of what?
什麼樣的刺青？
It was one of those Fighting Irish tattoos.
聖母院大學的吉祥物
I'm afraid if I report it they'll make me testify.
我怕說了他們會逼我作證
What do you think I should do?
我該怎麼做？
Tell the FBI.
告訴聯邦探員
If the guy's got a record, and I'm sure he does...
那傢伙一定有前科
...they'll have his tattoos on tile.
他們會有刺青的記錄
They'll ring him up the next day.
隔天就會逮捕他
Robbery, weapons. He'll get 30 years.
持槍搶劫，他會被判3 0年
Course, they'll worry someone's gonna come looking for the witness.
但他的同夥可能會來找證人算賬
The FBI will probably want to put you in WITSEC, you know, Witness Security.
FBI大概會保護你
You know, they'll probably put you somewhere, like, you know, in Cleveland...
你得搬到克利夫蘭或亞利桑那州
Or...
或是…你可以等
You have a card.
你有一張王牌
There's nothing says you gotta play it right away.
不必馬上就出牌
You're the one who's vulnerable in this situation right now.
你現在的處境很危險
The FBI are just people like anyone else.
聯邦探員也跟別人一樣
You have to look out for yourself, Claire.
你得替自己著想，克萊爾
Quite an expert.
你真是個專家
Not really.
並不是，只是常看電視
I watch a lot of CSI.
我很愛看《C S I犯罪現場》
So I'm a really big expert on all this. I know.
所以我真的瞭解很多
And Miami CSI and New York CSI.
我也看《C S I：邁阿密》和 《C S I：紐約>
All of them, I watch.
我全都愛看
You'll be well-prepared.
你隨時做好準備
And Bones.
還有《尋骨線索》
Do we know each other well enough for me to say that this truck is a little much?
我倆有熟到可容我說…
It's my work truck.
這是我工作用的車
If you have problems with your Prius I can throw it in the back.
你的油電車壞了可以直接載上去
How did you know I had a Prius?
你怎麼知道我開油電車？
Took a guess. I mean, it just seemed like a toonie car.
我猜的，雅痞會開這種車
-Why, do you really have a Prius? -Yeah.
-你真的開油電車？ -對
-Really? -I had a Prius.
-真的？ -我有過一輛？
-It got vandalized, of course. -What happened?
-後來遭到破壞 -發生什麼事？
-There were these guys and they started .... -What?
那埵釣Ё疇賰|…
I'm not sure if it was the same guys who trashed my car, but--
-我不確定是同一夥人 -一夥人？
They started getting, you know-- it started with yelling when I walked by...
我每次經過，他們都會亂罵
...and then it got really aggressive and ....
後來變得很誇張
What were they doing?
他們會做什麼？
Once glass bottles started getting thrown...
有一次直接丟玻璃瓶
They threw bottles at you?
他們向你丟玻璃瓶？
I’m fine. I just have to, you know, go the long way.
我沒事，我只得繞遠路而已
That's all. It doesn't matter.
沒有關係
No. You just have to live with it, I guess.
是啊，你只能忍氣吞聲
You remember what they look like?
你記得他們的長相嗎？
I need your help. I can't tell you what it is...
我需要幫忙 細節我不能說
...you can never ask me about it later, and we're gonna hurt some people.
你也別問，我們要去痛扁一些傢伙
Whose car are we gonna take?
要開誰的車？
Kenny with the white nose.
白鼻肯尼
-Hey, what's good, man? -Hey.
-有什麼好消息，夥計？ -嘿
-How you doing? -I hope you here to buy something.
-還好嗎？ -希望你是來買東西的
You roll up on a nigga, "Kenny with the white nose" like that.
你跑來敲黑鬼的門 還叫我白鼻肯尼
Well, we ain't here to play fucking Xbox.
我們不是來這堛措C戲的
-Yeah. -Wanna buy some dope, Kenny.
-好的 -我們想買點毒品，肯尼
-Cheap, shitty dope. -Yeah? Okay.
-便宜劣等的毒品 -是嗎？好的
-He sells no other kind. -Let me go find my box.
-他只賣這種毒品 -我去找盒子
-I'll be right back, okay? -Appreciate it.
-很快就回來，好嗎？ -謝謝
Kenny.
肯尼
We're in Charlestown.
我們在查爾斯敦
Worst heroin problem on the East Coast. Nigga Ken can't find his box.
東海岸最嚴重的毒品交易地 黑鬼肯尼又找不到他的盒子
You ever buy from this clown before?
你以前從他手上買過嗎？
I bought drugs from electrician Marty with the white nose.
我以前和他從電工馬帝那媔R毒品
All right.
好吧
Yeah, here we go. I got just what you need, brother.
好了，找到了 剛剛好是你們想要的，兄弟
-All right, here. -All right. Looks good to me, baby.
-好了，拿著 -好，看起來不錯，寶貝
-Thanks, partner. -Yes, sir.
-謝謝，夥計 -不用客氣
Hey, um...
嘿
...you know them Dominican kids always starting trouble on Medford Street?
那些經常在梅福德街生事的 多米尼加籍的年輕人
Know what unit they're in?
你知道他們在哪個區嗎？
Townie credit card.
用這個開門
-Who is it? -Open up.
-誰？ -開門
What the--'?
搞什麼？
You drinking beers up here, huh? You--
你在這堻黹s，對嗎？
That hurts, right? Fucking piece of shit.
很痛，對嗎？混蛋
Throw with your left?
你慣用左手？
-Fuck! -Oh, shit, that hurts, huh?
-該死 -可惡，很痛，對嗎？
-What the fuck? -That's a bitch, ain't it?
-你們在幹什麼？ -很痛苦，是嗎？
Deal gone south for you motherfuckers.
你的交易完蛋了，混蛋
-Too bad. -Who the fuck are you?
-太糟糕了 -你們到底是誰？
Shouldn't be up here fucking selling dope, I guess.
也許你不應該在這婼甈r品
Listen to me, we're coming back in a week.
聽我說，我們一個星期後回來
-If you're fucking here then... -Oh, shit.
-如果你還在這堙A那麼… -天啊
...this is happening again.
這樣的事還會發生
Let's go, we're done.
走吧，搞定了
Hey.
你幹了什麼好事？
Hey, chill, chill, chill, man. Chill. Chill, man.
-冷靜點，老兄，冷靜點 -現在你知道了吧？
Don't tell me to chill.
別叫我冷靜點
-Enough. Let's go. -What'd you do?
-夠了，走吧 -你幹了什麼？
-I don't know what you're talking about. -No?
-我不知道你在說什麼 -不知道？
Soccer. There goes college soccer, motherfucker.
你踢不了足球了，混蛋
-Fuck! -What'd you do?
-該死 -你要怎麼做？
-No? -I don't know. Aah!
-不知道？ -我不知道
See my face?
看到我的臉嗎？
Go tell the cops, all right?
儘管去報警
But just remember, I seen yours too.
不過我也看到你的臉
Fuck.
該死
I can't be up there killing people, man.
我不是跟你來殺人的
Hey, you brought me.
是你帶我來的
Desmond Elden?
戴斯蒙·艾登？
Yeah, works for Vericom. Never seen the inside of a jail cell.
替保安公司工作，沒坐過牢
Most of these guys got no-show jobs. Take down a truck...
這些搶匪的工作要曠班很容易 他們搶了運鈔車
...foreman goes, "Yeah, guy was here yesterday." He shows us a forged timecard.
工頭會說：「他昨天有來上班」
Can't play them games at Vericom because it's a public company.
保安公司是上市公司，很有制度
You don't show up, it's a recorded sick day.
沒上班就算是請病假
And Dezzy here, he's got some interesting sick days.
戴斯蒙一請病假就發生搶案
BankBoston, Cummins Armored, Arlington Brinks, Cambridge Merchants.
波士頓銀行、康明運鈔車 阿靈頓運鈔車、劍橋商業銀行
Jesus Christ.
老天爺
No, my father finally made it out to the suburbs,
沒，我爸終於搬到了郊區
What about your mother?
你媽呢？
I couldn't tell you. She left when I was 6.
不知道，我六歲時她就不見了
What happened?
發生什麼事？
She left.
她走了
Okay.
好吧
This sound woke me up.
我被一個聲音吵醒
At first I didn't know what it was.
一開始不知道是什麼
Sounded like an animal that got trapped.
聽起來像是被困住的動物
I never heard a man cry before.
我沒聽過大男人哭過
I came downstairs in my underwear.
我穿著內褲到樓下
I see my father in the kitchen.
看到我爸在廚房
First thing I remember was the ashtray.
我最記得的是煙灰缸
Must have been a hundred cigarettes in there.
至少有上百根煙蒂
Ash like a little mountain.
堆成一座小山
He stopped crying...
他不哭了以後
...was just sitting there watching TV on a little black-and-white.
就坐在那堿搋瞼桯q視
No sound.
沒開聲音
I think he just didn't know what else to do.
我猜他不知道還能做什麼
He looked at me standing there in the doorway in my Underoos.
他看到我穿著內褲站在走廊
He said, "Your mother left. She's not coming back."
然後說：「你媽走了，不會回來了」
Just like that.
就這樣
Smoking cigarettes and eating a TV dinner at 6 in the morning.
一大早六點 邊抽煙邊吃垃圾食品
We lost our dog the year before...
事發前一年我家的狗不見了
...and I wanted to make these posters...
我想做尋人啟事
...in case my mother was lost...
以免我媽只是迷路
...someone could call us...
有人會找到她
...like the guy who found our dog.
就像有人找到我家的狗一樣
To this day my father will tell you he helped me make them posters, but he didn't.
我爸總是說他有幫我做海報
Sat in the kitchen, drank a case of beer while I went out on School Street...
其實並沒有 他只坐在廚房喝了一箱啤酒
...asking people if they'd seen my mother.
到處問人有沒有看到我媽
Her name was Doris.
她的名字是朵莉絲
My grandmother had a place that's a restaurant in Tangerine, Florida.
我外婆在佛州開了一家餐廳
So I used to imagine maybe that's where she went.
我以前會想也許她去了那
Then I came to terms with the fact that doesn't really matter, you know?
後來才覺得這一切都不重要了
Wherever she went, she had a good reason to leave here.
不管她去了哪 一定有原因
She didn't wanna be my mother anymore...
她不想再當我的媽媽
...and she wasn't coming back.
也不會再回來了
And now you know a little bit about my family...
雖然你知道我家的一些事
...but I'm still not showing you my apartment.
我還是不會請你到我的公寓
How bad can it be?
會有多糟呢？
Oh, yeah.
好
Desmond Elden.
戴斯蒙·艾登
Systems tech at Vericom, 22 years old.
保安公司系統技師，2 2歲
Albert Magloan. Only in Boston is a guy named Albert Magloan.
艾柏特·麥格隆
Mr. Magloan never met a car he couldn't boost.
麥先生什麼車都能偷
The kind of talented individual...
他的才華洋溢
...that can start your Cherokee for you while you’re still looking for your keys.
你還在找鑰匙時，車子就被偷了
James Coughlin. Father was killed in prison, mother died of HIV.
詹姆斯·考克林
Shot Brendan Leahey by the cemetery behind Mishawum when he was 18.
1 8歲就在墓園旁殺死一個人
Pled it out. When the judge asked him why he did it, he said, "I didn't like the kid."
認罪減刑 法官問他為什麼殺人
Served nine years for manslaughter.
以過失殺人罪服刑9年
These guys plan and execute with sophistication and discipline.
他們的計劃和行動都非常精準
And that is not our boy Coughlin.
首腦絕對不是考克林
We think the architect is this guy, Coughlin's best friend, Doug MacRay.
而是這傢伙
Lives in the same house, dated Coughlin's sister...
住在一起，曾和考克林老妹交往
...who most likely mules for the Florist, who used to employ MacRay's father.
他大概替花店老闆運毒
You need a fucking Venn diagram for these people.
這些人的關係錯綜複雜
Mac Sr. got life for the Nashua job, which most of you should remember.
老麥因運鈔車搶案被判無期徒刑
Hijacked a bread truck up to New Hampshire...
他們搶新罕布什爾州運鈔車
...one of the guards saw his face...
其中一名警衛看到他的臉
...so they executed both of them with their own weapons.
於是就用警衛的佩槍殺死他們
Big Mads legacy is now no A car driver is allowed to leave the cab...
因為這起搶案
...even if there's a gun to his partner's head.
司機也不能下車
MacRay did eight months for going over the counter at a BayBank...
小麥因蓄意搶銀行服刑八個月
...with a nail gun after he washed out from pro hockey.
而進不了職業曲棍球隊
-Pro hockey? -Yeah, he was a big deal for a minute.
-職業曲棍球隊？ -他有一陣子很出名
Got drafted, went to camp, and here's the shocker:
被球隊簽下，去了訓練營
Started making trouble, fighting with guys.
結果和球員打架
-Don't they pay you to fight in hockey? -No, not the guys on your own team.
曲棍球不就是要打架嗎？
MacRay came home, got into the family business.
他回家加入家族事業
Same song, got into OxyContin.
也染上了毒癮
Hockey ship sailed with the narcotics.
再也不能打曲棍球了
Now, we are a long way away from a grand jury here.
我們還不能起訴他們
We'll never get 24-hour surveillance...
也不能2 4小時監視
...unless one of these idiots converts to Islam.
除非其中一個改信回教
So we build the case.
我們必須盡量搜證
All right, let's get to work.
好了，幹活吧
So I've been telling all my friends about you.
我跟我朋友提起你
-Oh, yeah? All good, I hope. -Yeah.
是嗎？ 你都說好話吧？
Oh, yeah. They say they're overcome with jealousy.
我猜她們一定都很嫉妒你
They can't believe your luck.
不敢相信你有多幸運
You moved to Charlestown, hooked up with a rock-breaking townie.
搬到查爾斯敦，和碎石民工約會
No.
錯
They just think it's a rebound.
她們只是覺得我需要慰藉
A rebound from what, the robbery?
因為那起搶案？
I don't know.
我不知道
I feel estranged from them somehow.
我和她們很疏遠
What? Why do you look like that?
怎麼了？為什麼這麼悲傷？
-My brother died on a day like this. -When was this?
我弟弟也是在這種日子去世
He was little. He had lymphoma.
他還小的時候長了淋巴瘤
So now on really sunny days I always think of someone dying.
所以我遇到晴天 就會想到有人去世
That's wrong, isn't it?
這樣不好，對吧？
No.
不
I'm sure he'd be glad you're thinking about him.
你想到他，他一定很開心
This is a good day.
這是好日子，我很開心
Good.
很好
Then you'll miss me while I'm gone.
很好，我不在你就會想我
Money, bitch.
把錢給我
Pop.
砰！
What the fuck you doing here? Huh?
你在這媟F嘛？
-Nothing. -Nothing? What's this?
-沒幹嘛 -少來，這是什麼？
-Who are you here with, huh? -No one.
-你在跟誰吃飯？ -沒人
-Let's get out of here. -You're telling me this is yours?
-這是…？ -沒別人，走吧
-Yeah. -Yeah? Fucking Hawaiian pizza?
夏威夷匹薩？
-Sit down. -Let's hit the road.
-坐下來，我才剛來 -閃吧，我得走了
-I gotta go. -Sit the fuck down. Just sit down.
給我坐下來，坐下
-Hi.
-嗨
-Hey. -Claire.
-嘿 -我是克萊爾
-I'm Jem. -Jim?
-我是小詹 -詹姆斯？
Jem. Jem. It's just Jem, yeah.
小詹，叫我小詹就好
I'm a friend of this loser right here.
我是這個窩囊廢的朋友
-Nice to meet you. -Sit down, sit down, relax. All right?
-幸會了 -坐下來，放輕鬆
So I saw your fucking Avalanche parked around the corner, so ....
我看到你的雪崩停在角落
The Avalanche?
-雪崩？ -貨車
-Dougy's quite the worker. -Yeah.
-道格熱愛工作 -對
Have you two known each other a longtime or...?
你們認識很久了嗎？
Since we were 6. We're like brothers. Right?
六歲就認識了，我們就像兄弟
But he's never mentioned a word about you.
可是他都沒提過你
The secrets with this one, you know, huh?
這小子愛搞神秘
Did you say your name was Jim or Jem?
你說你叫詹姆斯或小詹？
It's Ji--Je-- Well, it's both, actually.
小…其實兩個都是
Teachers, when we were growing up, used to always say:
我們從小一起上學老師都說：
"Hey, you can have this one. He's a real gem."
我不想「沾」上這小鬼
So I guess it kind of stuck.
於是大家都叫我小詹
Whatever. I don't know.
無所謂啦
So, what do you do for yourself there, Claire?
你是做什麼的，克萊爾？
Oh, I work at a bank. I'm a bank manager.
我是銀行經理
You're a bank manager? Sounds fun. What bank?
銀行經理 聽起來很好玩，哪家銀行？
Cambridge Merchants. Just over there.
劍橋商銀，就在那
Cambridge Merchants. Wait, that's the one that just got robbed, isn't it?
劍橋商銀，剛被搶的那一家？
It got robbed, yeah. It did, yeah.
沒錯，它剛被搶劫
I read about that. It's crazy.
我看到新聞，太扯了
So then how is it that you two met?
你們在哪婸{識的？
We met at a Laundromat.
自助洗衣店
Okay.
好吧
Love among the bleach, right?
是喔，漂白水之戀？
Hey, it happens more than you think.
這種事常發生
Hey, Claire, don't get too used to your life of leisure here.
嘿，克萊爾 你最好別太習慣常跟他約會
Dougy here, he's a real workaholic, you know.
道格是個工作狂
He's always taking his work home with him.
他老是把工作帶回家
Aren't you?
對吧？
-All right. -All right, brother.
-好吧 -好，兄弟
Take care of yourself, all right? Be good.
你要保重，乖一點
I'll see you at home. It was nice to meet you.
我們回家見 很高興認識你
You too.
我也是
Well, I guess you haven't been telling all your friends about me.
我猜你沒跟朋友提起我
Who you following, Jem? Me or her?
你在跟蹤誰？我或她？
I told you, I made the Avalanche.
我說過我只是看到你的車
Nothing to worry about. It's all under control.
別擔心她，我都搞定了
Oh, so you're trying to get us jammed up?
你想害死我們，是不是？
-Is that it? -I'm trying to get you jammed up.
是啊，我想害你
Tell me you got a move here, Dougy.
你這麼做最好是有原因
Because the only way I see it is you got sprung like a goddamn bear trap...
因為我看到 你就像一隻掉入陷阱的熊
...on some toonie pussy who happens to be the one goddamn person--Fuck!
迷戀唯一能指認我們的…
The one person that can give us to the fucking Feds.
該死！唯一能指認我們的證人！
Calm down, all right?
冷靜點，好嗎？
Don't you think we need to be smart right now?
你不覺得我們得隨機應變嗎？
-Smart? -Yeah.
-隨機應變？ -對
Let's start fucking all the witnesses. All right?
那就和每個證人上床吧
Yeah, I'm blowing the assistant manager. Am I smart now? Huh?
我要替助理經理吹喇叭，對吧？
And no, I didn't tell the other guys, only because they'd flip the fuck out.
放心啦，我不會告訴其他人
And I want them fucking ready for the next thing.
我要他們準備幹下一票
I told you, the next fucking thing's not ready.
我說過，下一票還沒準備好
Then make it ready.
那就快去準備好
I don't like the guards on the next thing, all right?
我很擔心下一票的警衛 好嗎？
One kid is like fucking G.l. Joe.
其中一個像特種部隊
He wears the vest on the outside, tucks his pants into his fucking combat boots.
防彈背心穿在外面
The truck's fucking waist-high.
那輛運鈔車載滿了鈔票
We'll end another truck with a driver...
我要找另一輛運鈔車
...who's a fucking fat kid with his fucking shit untucked...
警衛是個肥佬
-...who don't think he's Special Forces. -Yeah?
-看起來不像是特種部隊的 -是嗎？
All right, look, I know you're happy in Fuck City over there...
看來你和那小妞幹得很爽
...but I waited nine years in Walpole for you, motherfucker.
我可是在牢媯奶F你9年
Just nine years, that's all.
只有9年而已
I'm done waiting.
我不想要再等了
This is the last one. We're hitting pause after this.
這是最後一票，然後就收山
You hate prison but you can't wait to get caught.
你討厭監獄 然而你卻急著讓自己被捕
We get pinched, remember whose idea this was, okay?
要是被抓，記得這是誰的王葸
Be ready on Friday.
禮拜五準備好
Visitors, straight ahead.
訪客直走
-Who you seeing? -Stephen MacRay.
-你來見誰？ -史蒂芬·麥克雷
Twelve.
1 2號窗口
-Right down there. -Thanks, Lenny.
-那 -謝了，連尼
You all right? Every time I come up here now it's the red pajamas.
你還好吧？ 我每次來你都穿紅色囚衣
You still getting in trouble, Dad?
你還在惹麻煩嗎，爸？
Hey, you know how it is. Can't take no shit.
你很清楚，誰也別想惹我
You're getting a little old for that bullshit, aren't you?
你年紀大了，不能一直打架
Fucking Southie kids. They wanna run everything.
那些臭小子想掌控一切
Listen, you put a year together of good behavior and get your points down...
聽好，你只要一整年都表現良好
...you get classed out over to Norfolk, Dad.
就能被調到諾福克，爸
No one's gonna bother you there. Nobody fights, you know?
那堥S人會惹你，沒人會打架
They got fucking Ben & Jerry's ice cream and shit.
而且還能吃到冰淇淋
Well, some things you gotta deal with yourself, you know?
有些事一定要自己應付
All right.
好吧
I'm thinking about taking a trip.
我正在考慮離開一陣子
-Going dark for a minute. -Taking heat?
暫時避避風頭
Yeah, don't tell me.
少來，什麼做些改變
Either you got heat or you don't.
你不是被盯上，要不就沒有
I heard a bread truck got dropped.
聽說一輛運鈔車被搶
Oh, yeah? I didn't hear about it.
是嗎？我沒聽說
Okay.
好吧
You got five minutes. Five minutes.
你們只剩五分鐘！五分鐘！
Let me ask you something.
我想問你
In case I don't see you again.
萬一不會再見到你
How come you never...?
你怎麼從來…
How come you never looked for her?
你怎麼從來不去找她？
Looked for who?
找誰？
For Ma.
媽媽呀
For my mother. How come you never looked for her?
我媽呀，你怎麼不去找她？
How come you never tried to call nobody or look for her, or ask around?
你怎麼從來不問她在哪堙H
Look, when your mother left...
你媽離開後
...you cried so hard you were throwing up. All over the parlor.
你哭倒在客廳一直大吐特吐
So I told you if you looked around you might find her.
所以我跟你說也許找得到她
Just to give you an activity.
我只是讓你有事做
I didn't think you'd carry it like a fucking disease.
沒想到你像著魔一樣
What, you wanna think she was an angel?
你想把她想成天使？
Go ahead.
儘管想吧
But look out your front door.
但是看看你家附近
How many 22-year-old girls are out there...
有多少2 2歲女孩到處亂搞
...they're fucking around with kids they don't want...
生下她們不要的小孩
...and, you know, no sense in their heads.
她們的腦子堻ㄙ讀臟p也
And your mother wasn't no different.
你媽跟她們沒什麼不同
That's the hard truth.
這就是事實
I made my peace with it. You make yours.
我接受這事實，你也該接受
I didn't look for her because there was nothing to find.
我不去找她因為沒什麼好找的
Look, I gotta die five times before I get out of here...
聽好，我得在牢堳搕W五輩子
...but I'll see you again.
但我還會見到你
This side or the other.
今生或來世
So I saw your picture yesterday.
我昨天看到你的照片
-Are you sure it was me? -Yeah, I'm pretty sure.
你確定是我嗎？
-Oh, the Boys & Girls Club? -Yeah.
喔，兒童俱樂部？
It was under a "local heroes" banner.
對，你被列為地方英雄
Yeah. They got a real low standard for who qualities on that.
是啊，他們的標準定得很低
Apparently you were drafted.
你選上職業冰上曲棍球隊
Yeah. I was slow. And I couldn't skate backwards.
不過我溜冰很慢 而且我不會倒退溜
You're supposed to be able to skate backwards in pro hockey.
打職業賽一定要會倒退
But I could shoot, you know? I could hit anything with a hockey puck.
不過我很會射門
But I got drafted and I just didn't do what it took to make the team.
我在選拔時並不想努力進球隊
And when I got a second chance, I blew that too.
當我有第二次機會，也故意搞砸
They sent me home and that was it.
於是他們送我回家…就這樣
I look at that picture and I see a 20-year-old kid...
當我看到那張照片 2 0歲的孩子…
...who thinks he's, you know, got it all figured out.
我看到一個信心滿滿的年輕人
Right before he's about to throw it all away.
就在他準備放棄一切之前
Hey, I don't wanna rush anything, but can we go into your room?
我不是操之過急，但能進房間嗎？
Because my uncle the bus driver lives right across the way...
我叔叔就住在對面
...and he can see right into this apartment.
他可以看到你的客廳
-Yes. -Okay.
-好 -好吧
They win the game in overtime. Then you flip it over.
他們在延長賽贏了比賽
Then you go back to Fenway Park.
只要轉台就有棒球比賽轉播
Then you get another great ending to another ....
你會聽到另一場比賽…
--19, we walked through.
我們搜過1 9號公寓
Nothing appears disturbed.
沒有被侵入的跡象
In this apartment anyway.
至少這間公寓沒有
Where the fuck's the truck?
運鈔車在哪堙H
We shut and locked the door but...
我們關上並鎖好門了 但是…
-What happened to 08:45? -Late is what happened.
不是8點4 5分會到嗎？
Fucking douche bag.
王八蛋
Say your prayers. Here we go.
禱告吧，上吧
Here we go.
上吧
Gun!
槍！
Don't move!
別動！
-Go! Go! -Get back! Get back!
-走！走！ -回來！回來！
Get out of the way!
閃開！
Any units In the area, 10-61 In progress.
發生運鈔車搶案
The call went out!
他們報了警！
Fuck.
該死
Get out here, asshole, I got your friend.
出來，我抓到你朋友
Calm down. Put your gun away, all right? You're gonna get hurt.
冷靜點，把槍放下，你會受傷
Put that fucking gun down now. I got you, motherfucker.
把你的槍放下！我逮到你了！
Jesus!
天啊！
You should have stayed in the truck, cunt.
你應該留在車上的，王八蛋
Let's go!
快點！
What the fuck just happened?
發生什麼事？
-Goddamn it, I fucking told you. -Fucking shut the fuck up, all right?
該死，我早就告訴你！
-Fucking knew it. -Goddamn it!
-我早就知道 -可惡！
All right, drive. Just take it easy, all right? Take it easy. Drive slow. Drive normal.
冷靜點，開車，慢慢開
-Shit. -Ah, fuck.
-該死 -該死！
Driver, turn your engine off.
司機，把引擎熄火！
Hands where I can see them.
把手伸出來！
Fuck.
可惡
Shut the engine off now. Put your hands in the a--
把引擎熄火！把手…
Hit the engine block!
沖引擎開槍！
Go, go, go, go, go!
快…快…
Go to the fucking switch!
開到接應車那堙I
Fuck!
該死的！
How do you like that, motherfucker?
很爽吧，混蛋？
Let's go, let's go!
快，快！
-It's Dez. -Let's go, let's go!
-是戴斯 -快走，快走！
Drop it!
放下武器！
Let's go!
快點！
Dino.
迪諾
What?
什麼？
Close the bridge.
封閉大橋
-What? -Close the fucking bridge.
-什麼？ -封閉大橋！
Alpha 101, Alpha 412, Alpha 407...
Al01、A412 和A407警車
...en route to the north end of the bridge.
正趕去查爾斯敦橋北端
They're going for the bridge.
他們要去大橋！
Now, that's how you drive a fucking car.
這樣才算飆車嘛！
All the DNA in Charlestown.
全查爾斯敦居民的DNA
The fuck was that?
那到底是什麼意思？
He didn't wanna end up on the wall at the VFW.
他不想成為殉職警察的一分子
You print the inside of the van?
采過廂型車內的指紋嗎？
Frawl, the inside of the van is a volcano.
弗勞利，車內被燒得一塌糊塗
Just find something and make it look like something that looks like a print.
去找看起來像是指紋的東西
We don't have enough for a conviction. Fine.
沒有足夠證據起訴沒關係
But I need to get them in a room.
只要能訊問他們就夠了
Right now, they are burning the money bands at some bullshit safe house.
現在他們一定躲在哪媬N鈔票箍條
All their alibis were paid for a week in advance,
不在場證明也早就搞定了
We're not gonna pull any DNA off of this or off the switch car.
兩輛車都不會找到任何DNA
And that, as they say, is that.
這就是所謂的死胡同
This is the "not fucking around" crew. Find me something that looks like a print...
這些搶匪是狠角色
This "not fucking around" thing is about to go both ways.
因為我們也該耍狠了
Turn around for me, will you?
轉過去
-Mr. Coughlin. -Lawyer.
-考克林先生 -律師
-This is it? Just say what's here? -Yeah, go ahead. Read what's on the paper.
-就這樣？讀上面的東西？ -沒錯，讀吧，讀紙上的東西
All right.
好吧
"You aren't supposed to come out of the truck. You got him but who got me?
「你不應該從車堨X來 你掩護他，誰掩護我？」
Courier, you're gonna get hurt."
「庫媞腹A你不會受傷的」
It's kind of short.
很短
Go ahead, read what's on the page.
讀紙上的東西
Right there? Um ....
紙上的？
"You aren't supposed to come out of the truck."
「你不應該從車堨X來」
-Come on, come on. -"You got him but who got me?"
-繼續，繼續 -「你掩護他，誰掩護我？」
"Come here, get on the ground, before I pop your fucking teeth out!"
「過來，趴下，不然我會揍扁你」
Come on, read it. Read it all. There's about five things there.
快念完，總共有五句
What is it with you guys in Charlestown?
查爾斯敦人都是文盲嗎？
I don't wanna read that. This doesn't sound right.
我不想念，這些句子不合理
I'm not asking you, I'm telling you. Read the pages, please.
你沒有選擇，我命令你念
I'm trying to make this sound authenticious.
我只想念得跟真的一樣
Thanks.
謝謝
-Hey, Dougy, How are you? -Oh.
道格，你好嗎？
How you doing?
你好嗎，犯罪剋星？
What's happening, Dino?
迪諾，這是怎麼回事？
I know your father.
我認識你老爸
Yeah. Me too.
對，我也認識
Got a few years left on his bid.
他只剩幾年刑期
Yeah, one or two.
是啊， 一、兩年
I hear they got to the old guy.
聽說你老爸被整得很慘
Split him up the back.
屁眼被操到開花，那些禽獸
You'd think they'd go after a younger kid.
他們要幹也該找少年郎
I don't know. Making a statement, I guess.
不知道，我猜他們想殺雞儆猴
Townie crews ain't what they used to be.
查爾斯敦幫大不如前了
Dorchester...
多契斯特幫…
...Southie...
南區幫…
...looking to make a move.
全都想擴張勢力
Maybe you can change all that when you get up there.
也許你坐了牢就能阻止他們
Let me ask you a question. What do you call a guy...
問你一個問題
...who grows up with a group of people, gets to know their secrets...
有一個人和一群人長大
...because they trust him, and then turns around...
知道每一個人最隱私的秘密
...and use those secrets against them, put those people in prison?
然後用來對付他們
You'd call him a rat, right? You know what I call him?
你會叫他鼠輩，對吧？ 至於我呢
Dino the dago.
我會叫他迪諾
Those people made you a part of that community.
那些人把你當成自己人
What did they get for it?
結果有什麼下場？
Inside of the fucking can.
被你關進大牢
You know we lifted a print off the van? Right?
你知道我們採到指紋吧？
Special Agent Frawley...
特別探員弗勞利
"Douglas MacRay.
道格·麥克雷
You and your boys didn't just...
你和你的同夥
...roll a Star Market over in Malden for a box of quarters.
不會為了一點小錢搶超市
No, you decided to bang it out...
不，你們決定一早9點和警方槍戰
You fucking dummies shot a guard.
你們這些蠢蛋射殺一名警衛
Now you're like a half-off sale at Big and Tall, every cop is in line.
現在每一個警察都在排隊等著報仇
Fortunately, though, for you...
不過算你幸運
...this guard, who is two-thirds to a retard...
這個豬頭警衛奇跡般地活了下來
Now, if it were up to me...
如果我能決定
...and they gave me two minutes and a wet towel...
給我一塊濕毛巾和兩分鐘
...I would personally asphyxiate this half-wit...
我會親自捂死這個警衛
...so we could string you up on a federal M1...
以一級謀殺罪起訴你
...and end this story with a bag on your head...
你的下場會是被判死刑
This isn't fucking townie hopscotch anymore, Doug.
你們不再是玩家家酒了，道格
But I did want to say one thing.
不過我想說一件事
Just so we're both very, very clear.
這樣我們都一清二楚了
Because in these situations, sometimes, you know...
因為面對這些情況，有時候
...various parties will bandy about the possibility of sentence reduction...
各方會商討減刑的可能性
...for cooperation or otherwise assisting the--
看看他們是否與警方合作或是協助…
Assisting the prosecution.
協助訴訟
Not this time.
這次不行
You're here today so I could personally tell you...
在這 我要親口告訴你，你會死在牢
And so are all your friends.
還有你所有的朋友
No deal.
沒有合作減刑，不能妥協
And when that day comes...
當那一天到來
...when you start trying to be my hero collaborator so hard...
你很努力想當我的污點證人
...that I have to slap you to shut up-- And it will come...
我會打你一巴掌逼你閉嘴 一定會有那一天
...despite your pitiable, misguided, Irish omerta.
不管你們有什麼愛爾蘭精神
--when your code of silence finally gives way...
當你們為了怕在牢堻Q雞姦
...to fear of trafficking in cigarettes to prevent sexual enslavement...
違背你們所謂的緘默原則
...I just want you to know that it's gonna be me who tells you to go fuck yourself.
我要你知道我會告訴你，去死吧
Hey, next time you guys wanna take pictures of me, just call ahead.
下次你們想替我拍照先說一聲
You know, we can do better than a barbeque.
我們可以事先安排
A calendar shoot. You know?
也許可以露兩點拍一本月曆
Whatever you guys are into.
你們喜歡怎樣都行
FBI car antennas are half-inch matte black...
聯邦警車的天線長約半英吋
...about three-quarters the way down the rear windshield.
裝在後車窗底下三分之二的地方
Stacie are pigtailed...
州警警車天線多了一根
...B.P.D., half and half.
波士頓警車裝的是雙極天線
Every peewee in the town knows what an FBI rear antenna looks like.
這些就連三歲小孩都知道
So, in the future, if you guys are gonna try to be slick...
下次你們想躲得更隱密
...be slicker than a 6-year-old.
至少要比六歲小孩更厲害
I gotta get back to work.
我得回去工作，我能走了嗎？
Good luck with that print.
祝你們採到指紋
Good morning, Cambridge Savings.
劍橋商銀，早安
Claire Keesey, please. She's the manager.
我找銀行經理克萊爾基席
Oh, she's no longer working here.
喔，她不在本銀行工作了
-Since when? -Friday.
-幾時開始的？ -禮拜五
Just get the warrant. Land, cell, e-mail, fax, Skype. The whole fucking thing.
弄到搜索票 監聽手機、網路電話
-Oh, my God, Doug, -Took me forever trying to pick it out.
-我的天啊，道格 -我花了很長時間挑選
-Yeah, it's beautiful. -Is that all right?
-是的，很漂亮 -還可以吧？
Yeah, but I can't accept that from you. I can't take that,
不錯，但是我不能接受，不能
Why not? You can hawk it. I'm not taking it back.
為什麼？你可以賣掉它 我不會向你要回它
No. I mean, you can't--
不，我是說，你不能…
Keep it. Come on, sit down. Sit down.
拿著它，過來，坐下，坐下
-Sit down. -Okay.
-坐下吧 -好的
I quit my job today.
我今天辭掉了工作
What?
什麼？
What are you gonna do?
你要做什麼？
I have a little cushion.
我要緩和一下
You know...
聽我說
...people get up every day, they do the same thing.
人們每天起來都做著同樣的事
They tell themself they're gonna change their life one day and they never do.
他們對自己說，某天他們會改變 自己的生活，但他們從不去改變
I'm gonna change mine.
我要改變我的生活
Why don't you do it with me?
你不如跟我一起改變
Go somewhere.
到另一個地方呆呆
I got a little sofa put away.
我攢了些錢想出去走走
Give it a shot.
一起去吧
Well, where would we go?
我們去哪堙H
Wherever you want. I don't know.
你想去哪奡N去哪堙A我不知道
See what we got there.
看看那堛滷〞p吧
Doesn't have to be a big thing, you know? I thought about going down to...
這不是什麼大不了的事
...see if my grandma's place is still there. Tangerine, Florida.
我想去看看我奶奶的房子是否還在 它在佛羅里達橘子鎮
But I'll go to any town named after a food.
我會去任何以食物命名的鎮子
Grapefruit, Michigan. Watermelon, New Mexico.
密歇根柚子鎮，新墨西哥西瓜鎮
Just pick it on a map.
在地圖上挑選就可以
You ever read that paper "The Town"?
你讀過一份叫《鎮子》的報紙嗎？
-The free paper? Yeah. -Uh-huh,
那份免費報紙？讀過
I was clearing my foyer the other day...
有天我在清理大廳
...and there was a picture of the guys who were harassing me in the bricks.
看到上面登了一個曾經在街區 騷擾我的人的照片
-Yeah? -Mm-hm.
是嗎？
It was an article about how one of them got shot.
文章說他們其中一人中槍了
-Say who did it? -No.
-說了是誰幹的嗎？ -沒有
Local gangsters, apparently.
很明顯是當地歹徒
I guess that's what you get for being out on the street dealing drugs.
我想那就是在街上販毒的結果
What makes you say they were dealing drugs?
你怎麼會認為他們在販毒？
I grew up out there, Claire. Believe me, that kid was selling drugs.
我在那堛齯j，克萊爾 相信我，那個人在販毒
What do you want me to say?
那你要我怎麼說？
I feel bad the kid who was terrorizing you ran into the wrong guys?
我該為那個騷擾你的傢伙被襲擊 而感到難過嗎？
Believe me, I don't.
相信我，我不會這樣
You know, I care about you. I don't wanna see you get hurt.
我在乎你，我不想看到你受到傷害
You don't go after women.
你不能欺負女人
He hurt you, someone hurt him. Too bad. That's the way it goes.
他傷害你，其他人來傷害他 太糟糕了，但世道就是這樣
You know? That's karma.
知道嗎？這就是報應
I don't think karma works like that.
我想報應不是這樣的
Well, however it works, it worked out bad for them kids, you know?
不管它是怎樣 那些傢伙的結果都好不到哪去
And I'm not gonna shed a tear over it.
我也不會為此而流一滴眼淚
Let's go get some food, okay?
我們去吃點東西，好嗎？
Frawl.
弗勞利
What is it?
什麼事？
See if you can recognize the voice.
看看你認不認得對方聲音
Hey, can I come over? I want to talk to you.
嘿，我能過去嗎？我想跟你談談
Yeah. Where have you been?
好，你跑去哪堣F？
Sorry, I got held up.
抱歉，我有事耽擱
I'm coming over from my place.
我要從我家過去
Will you come down the back and let me in?
你能下樓讓我進去嗎？
Hadn't realized you'd left your job at the bank.
我不知道你辭掉銀行的工作
I'm sorry, was I supposed to notify someone?
抱歉，我應該通知你們嗎？
Fancy.
很漂亮
Yeah. It was a gift.
是啊，這是禮物
Look, I think maybe you should go.
聽著，我想你應該走了
We have our suspects.
我們找到了嫌犯
I came by to share this with you.
我是來給你看照片的
James Coughlin.
詹姆斯·考克林
Albert Magloan.
艾柏特·麥格隆
Desmond Elden.
戴斯蒙·艾登
Part of a crew that we tied into the bankjob at North End...
他們是北區銀行搶案…
...and at least three other armored car robberies.
和至少三起運鈔車搶案的嫌犯
Look familiar?
認得他嗎？
You opened the safe for him.
你替他打開銀行金庫
He left you unharmed...
他沒傷害你
...and now the two of you are carrying on a relationship about which you lied to the FBI.
你們正在交往，你卻說謊
I was wrong.
我當時說錯了，你是需要律師
Something wrong with the apartment?
公寓有問題嗎？
No, Florist.
沒有，是花店老闆
Florist? What?
-他怎樣？ -他有新的一票
-Oh, Jesus Christ. -It's large, Dougy.
-天啊 -很大的一票
-It's large. -We're smoked. Punt it.
我們被盯上了，交給別人
-Who else is gonna buy it? -You should've thought about that...
-還有誰會買它？ -你應該想想這個
...before you kept breaking the guy off for 40 dimes.
再和那個傢伙斷絕聯繫 那只不過是小錢
-There's an expectation for me. -I'll correct it.
-我希望能賺更多錢 -我會處理的
-Oh, you will? Okay. -Yeah. Look.
-是嗎？好吧 -沒錯，聽著
Look, pick up an extra guy. All right? Or go with three guys.
另外找人或是你們三個自己幹
Or fucking be smart and boot it.
聰明的話就拒絕
Oh, so you're not going?
你不參一腳？
No.
是的
And why's that?
為什麼？
Because we got a ton of heat on us, for one thing.
因為我們被盯得很緊
We'll put a move on. We've done it a hundred times.
我們能像以前一樣躲過他們
You know what? Forget it. Do what you want to do. I'm done.
算了，隨便你，我不幹了
-What? What? -I'm done.
-什麼？ -我不幹了
-You're done? -What does it sound like?
-你不幹了？ -你沒聽懂嗎？
-I don't know. What's that mean? -What you think it means?
-不曉得，什麼意思？ -你覺得呢？
What does that mean? Sounds like a bunch of bullshit.
你不幹了？聽起來是屁話
I'm putting this whole fucking town in my rear-view.
我這麼說吧，我要離開這
There's people I can't let you walk away from.
有人就是不准你離開
What?
什麼？
Who?
誰？
Come on.
少裝了
Are you serious, Jimmy?
你是說真的嗎？
She's not my kid.
她不是我的小孩
I mean, come the f--Cut it out.
拜託，少來了
All you give a fuck about is coke and Xbox...
你只會吸毒和打電動
...now you're trying to play it off like you care about Shyne?
現在卻突然關心起小珊，拜託
Know what your problem is? You think you're better than people.
你知道你的問題嗎？
Mr. Fucking-Clean. Mr. Fucking-Goddamn-High-and-Mighty.
老是高高在上、自命清高
I'm better than all these people. I'm better than everybody.
我是比這堛漕C個人都好
But you grew up right here.
但你是在這堛齯j的
Same rules that I did.
要遵守一樣的規矩
Okay.
好吧
What else?
還有什麼？
Who the fuck's the father?
孩子的父親到底是誰？
-I know I'm not. -You were the one fucking her.
-我知道我不是 -跟她上床的是你
Yeah, I wasn't the only one, brother.
沒錯，但我不是唯一一個，夥計
Okay? She knew I knew I'm not the father...
好嗎？她知道我不是父親
...and I have enough respect for her not to ask her.
我出於對她的尊重，所以沒去問她
Because I don't think she knows.
因為我想她不知道是誰
I don't wanna shatter your illusions here, partner.
我不粉碎你的幻想，夥計
There aren't enough free clinics in Mattapan...
麥特潘沒有足夠的免費診所
...to find out who the father of that kid is.
去讓你弄清楚那個孩子的父親是誰
I don't know who the fuck you think you are either.
我也不知道你對自己的看法
You aren't letting me or not letting me do shit, all right?
你不准我離開？想都別想
Here's a little cheat sheet for you.
讓我老實告訴你吧
It's never gonna be me and you and your sister and Shyne...
我、你、你妹和小珊…
...fucking playing house up there.
不可能在這堛戛a家酒！
All right? You got it? Get that in your fucking head!
瞭解嗎？接受事實吧！
I'm tired of your one-way fucking bullshit.
我受夠了你的霸道！
If you wanna see me again, come down and visit me in Florida.
你想再見到我，到佛州找我吧
Cunt.
混球
In the 302...
在供詞中
...Feds have me dropping Brendan right here.
調查局他們說 我在這堸絞憧珀黤n
I got him back on Tibbetts.
其實是在提貝特街
Shot him right in the chest.
對著他的胸口開了幾槍
I remember he looked at me.
我記得他當時看著我
I don't know who was more fucking surprised he wasn't dead, him or me.
看到他沒死，我不知道是誰更驚訝 不知道是他還是我
We just kind of stood there...
我們只是站在那
...for a second, like, waiting for some shit to happen. I don't know what.
我們似乎在等待著什麼事發生 我不知道是什麼
He started running.
他跑了起來
Fucking guy ran 100 yards with a bullet in his heart, Dougy.
那傢伙中彈後跑了一百碼
I mean, the fucking guy should've ran track. You know what I'm saying?
他應該參加田徑隊，瞭解嗎？
I didn't ask you to do that.
我並沒有說要你殺他
Yeah, well, you didn't have to, Dougy. Come on.
你不必說，拜託
They told me Brendan was coming down here to roll up on you with a Glock 21,
他們說布蘭登要來這堭你
so I came over here, and I put him in the fucking ground.
所以我就趕來把他幹掉
Did nine years for it.
結果坐了9年牢
Now, you don't gotta thank me...
你不必謝我，但你不能離開
I'm grateful for everything you done for me.
我很感激你為我做的一切
Your family took me in when my father went away.
我爸入獄後你家人收容了我
You're like a brother to me.
你就像我的親兄弟
But I'm leaving.
但是我要離開
Gonna shoot me?
你要殺我？
Go ahead.
儘管想吧
But you're gonna have to shoot me in the back.
不過你得從我背後開槍
-Don't get up. -All right.
-不用起來 -好
How you doing, Fergie?
你好，付老大
Listen, just wanted to stop by and tell you myself...
我只想過來親自告訴你
...whatever this thing is you got going on...
你安排的這一票
...I think my guys can handle it without me. You know what I mean?
我的夥伴沒有我也能做
I wouldn't hire them without you.
沒有你我就不會找他們了
And I wouldn't hire you without them.
沒有他們我也不會找你
You're a unit.
你們是一個團隊
Look, with all due respect, I didn't come here for a debate.
恕我直言，我不是來爭辯的
I'm not doing it.
我不幹
So, you know, work it out however you can. I ....
隨便你要怎麼安排，但是…
Calm down. Okay?
別緊張
It goes against my better judgment...
雖然這違背我的原則，但…
...but just out of respect, smooth things over...
這是出於對你的尊敬
...just take this for it, all right?
請你收下來
Not gonna cut it.
這樣不行
Do you think I'm gonna put Joe Flipperhead on this?
你以為我會隨便找人代替你？
You're gonna do what I ask.
你要聽我的命令
Not gonna cut it, huh?
這樣不行，是吧？
Okay.
好吧
Let me ask you something. Who the fuck do you think you are?
我問你，你以為你是誰呀？
The only guy in Charlestown with a gun?
查爾斯敦唯一有槍的人？
You guys run numbers and pump dope.
你們當組頭和藥頭
You're an old guy who don't know his glory years are behind him.
你只是不知道自己是過氣老頭
I ain't fucking working for you. Got it?
我不替你做事，瞭解嗎？
You got a problem with that, I live at 551 Bunker Hill Street. Stop by anytime.
不爽的話，我住在邦克街551號 隨時來找我
You know where to find me.
你知道地方
You're gonna do this for me...
你不替我幹這一票我就閹了你
...like I clipped your daddy's.
就像我閹了你爸一樣
Don't talk about my father.
別提起我老爸
Son, I knew your daddy.
孩子，我認識你老爸
He worked for me for years. Years.
他替我做了好多年的事
Then he wanted his own thing.
後來他想自立門戶
You play the horses?
你賭馬嗎？
You know, they either geld a horse with a knife...
他們不是用刀子閹掉賽馬
...or with the chemicals.
就是用化學藥物
When your daddy said no to me...
當你老爸說不幹了
...I did him the chemical way.
我就用藥閹了他
Gave your mother a taste.
然後讓你媽吸毒，讓她上癮
She doped up good and proper.
她很快就變成毒蟲
Hung herself with a wire on Melnea Cass.
最後用鐵絲上吊自殺
And you? Running around the neighborhood, looking for her.
而你還到處跑來跑去找她
Your daddy didn't have the heart to tell his son...
你爸不忍心告訴他兒子
...that he was looking for a suicide doper who was never coming home.
他在找一個已經自殺的毒蟲
If there's a heaven, son, she ain't in it.
如果有天堂，她不在那
I hear you got a nice, sweet new girlfriend.
聽說你有個漂亮女友
Lives on the park.
住在公園附近
I don't want to send her funeral arrangement to your house...
我不想把她的送葬花圈送到你家
...but I will if I have to.
但是有必要我就會
Now I know where to find you.
現在我知道去哪塈銣A了
Claire.
克萊爾
Claire?
克萊爾？
-Hey. -Get out.
-嘿 -出去
You okay?
你沒事吧？
-Hold on one second.
-等一下
I have this on 911.
我會打電話報警
All right, you need to give me a chance to explain myself first. Okay?
你得先給我機會解釋
No. You had a chance.
不，你有過機會
Who talked to you?
誰跟你談過？
The FBI, Doug.
FBI探員，道格
You have to listen to me.
你得聽我說，你得讓我解釋
-There's a lot going on here, Claire-- -No, you go to fucking hell!
-事情很複雜 -不，你下地獄吧
-Fucking hell. -All right, all right.
下地獄吧
All right. All right.
好，好，別激動
Why did you do this to me?
你為什麼要這樣對我？
Claire, I'm sorry. Okay?
克萊爾，對不起，好嗎？
I was gonna tell you. I came over here that night to tell you.
那天晚上我本來要來告訴你
What, the night you fucked me? ls that your thing?
你上我那晚？你愛這樣玩？
It's not enough to terrorize someone, you have to fuck them too?
威脅別人不夠，還要幹他們？
-Listen to me. Calm down, okay? -No. No. Get out. Get out!
-聽我說，冷靜點 -不！給我出去！
You don't ever let me see you again. Never, never.
別再讓我見到你，瞭解嗎？
I'm taking off for a while.
我要離開一會
Are you taking heat?
你要帶上我嗎？？
Well, when are you coming back?
那你什麼時候回來？
You know about this thing for Fergie Jem wants me to do?
記得付老大想讓我做的事嗎？
Yeah.
沒錯
Tell him I say yes for me, will you?
替我轉告他我同意了，好嗎？
All right.
好吧
I'm in.
我加入
But if anything happens to her...
但是她出事或我覺得她會出事
...I'm coming back here.
我就會回來這
And I'm gonna kill both of you in your own shop.
在你們的花店做掉你們
Hey, Claire?
嘿，克萊爾？
I just wanna talk to you, just for two minutes. Okay?
我只想跟你談兩分鐘，好嗎？
Come on.
拜託
Claire, I would never hurt you.
克萊爾，我絕不會傷害你
I don't know what you would-- Don't fucking touch me.
我不知道你會做什麼，別碰我
All right.
好吧
I'm sorry.
很抱歉
Just listen to me for a second, all right?
聽我說一下，好嗎？
I will never lie to you again.
我不會再騙你了
-Really? -Yes, I promise you.
-真的嗎？ -真的，我保證
Ask me anything you want. I'll tell you the truth.
-問我什麼我都會說實話 -為什麼？我不相信你
Because you'll fucking hate the answers.
你會痛恨我的答案
-You knew I was the manager in the bank? -Yup.
-你知道我是銀行經理對吧？ -對
-Were you following me? -Yes.
-你是來跟蹤我的？
How many banks have you robbed?
你搶過幾家銀行？
Six trucks, two banks.
6輛運鈔車，2家銀行
Have you ever killed anyone?
你有沒有殺過人？
No.
沒有
Think about it.
考慮一下
All right?
好嗎？
I will never lie to you, I will never hurt you...
我不會騙你，我不會傷害你
...and if I lose you, I will regret that for the rest of my life.
假如我失去你 我會終生悔恨
Just wait for me.
請你等我
You know, it's funny. I can see your daddies' faces in you.
很有趣 我從你們臉上看到你們老爸
All of youse.
你們全都提醒我還在擂台上
Still taking the punches. Still ahead on points.
還在挨打，還在得分
Now, I have a fellow on the inside there.
現在，我有一個線人
He likes to play the ponies. Has a gambling sickness.
他喜歡賭馬，賭癮很重
He couldn't pick a horse to save his fucking life.
而且他老是賭輸
But courtesy of this sick man...
但是拜他所賜…
...I have this, Hm?
我有這個
Well, the gang's all here.
他們全都到齊了
The cash is brought out and stacked 15 minutes before the van does the pickup.
現金被運走前十五分鐘被拿出來
That is when you hit.
趁這時候下手
And Monday morning, after a four-game stand with New York...
星期一一早，經過四場對紐約的球賽
...60,000 beers, food, merchandise, total haul:
六萬罐啤酒、食物和周邊商品 總共是…
Three and a half million.
3 5 0萬
Taking down the cathedral of Boston.
搶劫波士頓紅襪隊球迷的聖殿
Priceless.
無價
How long you think it's gonna take Rusty to dump the inside man...
洛帝做掉線人…
...when this thing's over?
要多久時間？
Well, he should have picked better horses.
他應該挑更好的賽馬
This is gonna be a motherfucker. You know that, right?
你知道幹這一票很困難
Well, if they were easy, kid, everybody would do them.
如果很容易，大家都會幹
Lined into right Held. A base hit. Youkilis is headed for third base.
一壘安打，尤基奡絮]向三壘
Hey, Bobby. Yeah, three Buds.
巴比，三罐啤酒
Seem to be having a bit of a staring contest over there.
看來那傢伙一直在盯著你
What can I say?
沒辦法，男人就是喜歡我
I bet they do.
那是一定的
I was at a bar one night, right?
有一晚我在一家酒吧
There was this guy there going around to all the ladies...
有個傢伙在和那些女士搭訕
...and telling them that he was judging a hugging contest.
他告訴她們他在評判一場擁抱比賽
Some of them actually bought it, right?
她們其中一些人相信了他
So he throws his arms around them, rubs their back, grabs their ass.
所以他開始擁抱她們 摸她們的背，抓她們的屁股
Charming.
非常可愛
Finally I get sick of it and I go up to this guy...
最後我感到厭煩了 我走到那個傢伙的跟前
...and I tell him that I am judging a face-punching contest.
對他說我在評判一場揍人比賽
By the way, I'm here tonight judging a fucking contest.
對了，我今晚是來這 評判一場上床比賽的
What are you doing down here?
你來這兒幹嘛？躲人？
I work for the FBI.
我是聯邦探員
Me too.
我也是
Well, you must be new.
你一定是菜鳥
You're all right.
你還不賴
It doesn't mean you're getting fucked, though.
但是不代表你能上我
You gotta chase the rabbit if you want the tail.
你想吃兔肉就得追兔尾巴
My mom taught me that.
我媽教我的
You used to hang around with Doug MacRay a little bit, huh?
你和道格·麥克雷在一起過？
How do you know Dougy?
你怎麼會認識他？
We sort of work together.
我們算是同事
Sand and Gravel?
砂石公司？
No. No, no.
並不是
You a pretty decent judge of size?
你很會看大小嗎？
Depends.
看情況，什麼的大小？
How big would you say that is?
你看這有多大？
Six inches?
6英吋？
Over or under?
比它大或比它小？
Under.
比它小
Wrong.
錯了，是6點14英吋
I know everything there is to know about money.
我知道鈔票的一切
.0043 inches.
厚度：零點零零四三英吋
about one gram.
重量：大約一共克
Which is interesting...
這一點很有趣
...because that means that this $20 bill isn't even worth its own weight...
這代表二十元鈔票 不值等重的毒品
So how does it work?
你們是怎麼販毒的？
Bartender gets a call...
酒保接到電話
...you pick up a package at point A, deliver it to point B...
你到A點拿貨送到B點
...the Florist gives you C?
花店老闆再給你錢？
You're thinking of running out on me.
你想逃跑
It's not that simple. Because, you see...
恐怕很難喔
...I start waving this around in here...
我只要揮一揮警徽
...bad for you.
你就會倒大霉
I want a lawyer.
我要律師
Good. Get one.
很好，去找一個
I mean, it's all about protecting yourself, right?
你總得保護自己，對吧？
Not even yourself. Your daughter.
不只是你，還有你女兒
Don't talk about my daughter.
別扯到我女兒
How long were you with MacRay?
你跟麥克雷在一起多久？
All my life.
一輩子
In all those years that you were together...
你們在一起這麼多年
...how many diamond necklaces did he give you?
他給過你幾條鑽石項鏈？
All right, he-re's the deal. Looks like we're pretty dialed in.
好了，過程是這樣的 看來我們掌握了足夠信息
Dez took the van home over the weekend...
戴茲在週末把麵包車開回家
...so that should work.
這應該沒問題
He"s meeting bug eyes at the plant on Monday.
他星期一在工廠和甲蟲眼見面
Krista booked the rooms, set up the outfits, and made the New Hampshire run.
克麗絲塔訂好房間，準備好裝備 讓新罕布夏州動起來
That's what I got, How you looking?
這是我弄到的 你的事辦得怎麼樣？
All right, the tools are set.
工具齊全了，去拿防彈背心
You know, this thing goes right...
幹完這一票
...could be your turn to step away too.
你也能收山
Yeah. Sure.
是啊
What am I gonna do, Dougy, huh?
我還能幹什麼？
Go down to Margaritaville, drink me half a yard and fall off fucking bar stools?
跑去酒吧，喝個爛醉
Do me a favor.
幫我個忙
The weight of this thing...
這一票太大，至少要想個退路
You know the funniest thing about being in prison?
你知道坐牢最可笑的是什麼？
Guys pretending that they wanna get out.
囚犯假裝他們想要出獄
Fuck.
該死
You ever hear the old-timers call a guy a "50-pound horse"?
你聽過以前的人 稱一種人為「50磅的馬」嗎？
"Fifty-pound horse"? No.
「50磅的馬」？沒有
All right. Ahem.
好吧
A guy's walking with two horses, right?
一個人拉著兩匹馬出行
One horse is carrying a hundred pounds, the other one's got 50.
其中一匹馬載著一百磅的東西 另一匹載著50磅
Now, the hundred-pound horse falls over dead. So the guy's like, "What the fuck?"
那匹載一百磅東西的馬突然死了 那個人感到很鬱悶
Takes the hundred-pound sack, puts it on the 50-pound horse.
他把那一百磅的麻袋放到載著 50磅東西那匹馬的背上
Then that 50-pound horse, he won't move,
那匹載著50磅東西的馬不肯動
He won't take one step with another pound on his back.
它怎麼也不肯載多一磅東西
That's me.
那就是我
This is all I know.
我只知道這點
I can't do any more time, Dougy.
我不能再坐牢
So if we get jammed up...
要是有警察，我們要開戰
All right?
好嗎？
Mule.
那是騾子
What's that?
什麼意思？
The story the old-timers tell...
以前的人說的那個故事
...it ain't a horse.
它不是馬
It's a 50-pound mule.
它是載著50磅東西的騾子
See you out there.
再見
What time did he get here?
他什麼時候到這堛滿H
Six a.m. according to the GPS we have on his truck.
根據他車上全球定位系統 早上六點
So we alerted you.
所以我們通知了你
Pop the door, kick their nuts in.
衝進去，制服他們
We should wait for them to commit a crime, don't you think, Dino?
我們要等他們犯案 不是吧，迪諾？他們沒有換車
Ran a cue hot on the parking lot.
停車場出現情況 那輛麵包車很可疑
Call SWAT now.
立刻叫反恐特警組過來
FBI! Open the door!
聯邦調查局，把門打開
-FBI! -Open the door! Open it!
-聯邦調查局 -把門打開…
Open the door! Open it!
把門打開，快點
FBI! FBI!
聯邦調查局
You brought the whole fucking cavalry for me?
你們帶了一支部隊來抓我？
I'm unarmed, you motherfuckers.
我沒有武器，混蛋
Fuck are you doing here, Kris?
你跑來幹嘛？
I need to talk to you.
我得跟你談談
Not a great time, hon.
現在不是時候，甜心
-I know, -You know?
-我知道 -你知道？你要什麼？
Here you go.
拿著
Dez told me you were here.
好吧，戴斯說你會在這
I wanna see you before you go.
你走之前我想見你
Kris, you could do 30 years for walking in the door.
克莉絲，你光是進來 就可能被判3 0年
Okay? Do you understand that? For being here.
知道嗎？ 你算是共犯，瞭解嗎？
You can't be bringing your kid in here, you got it? You can't stay.
不能把孩子帶來 也不能留下來
I don't wanna stay, I wanna go with you.
我不想留下來，我想跟你去
-I wanna change too, Dougy. -Christ.
-我也想改變 -天啊
Why the fuck can't I change? I could be a different person.
為什麼不行？我可以改變
Jesus Christ.
老天爺
You tell me what you want me to do. I'll be whoever you want me to be,
你要我怎樣我就怎樣
I'm leaving with somebody else.
我要和別人離開
Oh, yeah?
是嗎？
Yeah.
沒錯
Why isn't she here then?
她怎麼不在這堙H
Come on. What do you want me to tell you?
你要我說什麼？
She's going away with you, why isn't she here?
她要跟你走，那她怎麼不在這堙H
Where is she? She's not here.
她在哪堙H她不在這
-Such a trashy little fuck pad. -Take it easy.
-什麼爛房間嘛？ -冷靜點
After a Tiffany necklace, I thought a room at the Ritz.
你送她蒂芙尼鑽鏈 該到五星飯店才對啊
What'd you say?
你說什麼？
Where did you hear that? Where'd you hear about a necklace?
鑽鏈的事你是從哪兒聽來的？
A little bird.
有人說的
Fucking smartass. Who told you that? Who told you about a necklace?
誰說的？誰跟你說鑽鏈的事？
You're getting the fuck out of here. Let's go.
你給我滾出去
Come here, honey. I know, it's gonna be okay. It's all right.
小乖，不會有事的
-We're coming with you. -You're getting out of here.
-我們要跟你去 -你給我滾
Dougy, we're fucking coming with you.
道格，我們要跟你去
It's time to go, Okay? Here we go.
該走了，來吧，該走了 甜心，好嗎？
-I'm not leaving here. -Let's go.
-我不走 -走吧，克莉絲
-I'm not fucking leaving. -Take the kid home.
-我死也不走 -把孩子帶回家
Get the fuck off me!
放開我！我自己會走
Don't you say no to me!
不准跟我說不！
Take this.
拿這把
Hey.
嘿
Will you quit fucking doing that? You're making me nervous.
喂，別一直瞄，你會害我緊張
Yeah, we got a DWI over here, one car.
這媯o生酒駕車禍
Coughlin, Kristina. She had a kid with her.
克莉絲·考克林，還有個小孩
The mother's at Mass General. She wanted me to call you.
她媽在醫院，她要我打給你
All right, yeah. I'll be right there.
好，我馬上趕去
Officer.
警官
Yeah. Let's go.
走吧
Down here.
跟我來
There's the door.
門在那
And remember, you never fucking saw me.
記住，你們沒看過我
Okay.
好吧
Dr. Forrest, dial 112, please.
弗奡粟S醫生，請撥1 1 2
Here he is, Mr. Six-Inches.
他來了，6英吋先生
What happened?
發生什麼事？
You're a crimestopper, figure it the fuck out.
你是犯罪剋星，自己想呀
Sweetheart.
小姐
I know you have oxycodone, cocaine and alcohol in your system.
我知道你除了喝酒還有嗑藥
I know that you have five cars registered in your name.
你名下也有五輛車子
And I know right now, your daughter is sitting in the back of a state van...
現在你女兒 正坐在州政府的廂型車
... being driven by a stranger to the Department of Social Services.
司機是社福局的社工
So how long you wanna do this?
你要跟我耗多久？
I'm a person, you know?
我也是個人啊
A person who's gonna need a plea agreement...
對，你還想見到你的孩子 就得認罪合作
Why is it always I'm the one who's getting used?
我為什麼老是被利用？
What do you have?
你知道什麼？
Knowing just that...
我只知道…
...Dougy's going away after.
之後道格就要離開
Wait, what after? After what?
什麼之後？
Krista, I need you to be smart here.
克莉絲，你得學聰明點
This could be a big moment for Shyne.
這對小珊是個重要時刻
Make a huge difference in her life.
會完全改變她的生命
We can help you, sweetheart.
我們能幫助你，甜心
-You there? -I'm here.
-你在嗎？ -我在
-All set. -Okay. Go ahead.
-準備好了 -好，動手吧
All set.
搞定了
Who called 911?
是誰報警的？
You the guys who called 911?
你們報警嗎？
No one from here called.
沒人報警
Nah, we didn't--It wasn't us.
不是我們
We got a 911 call.
我們接到電話
Robbery, guys. Come on.
有人報警說搶劫
-Let me call Mike. -We just walked past Mike.
讓我打給麥克
Hey, look, guys, We got a distress call. All right?
我們接到報案電話 到底是誰打的？
-So who made the call? -Nobody called from here.
這堥S人打電話
No one called? What are we doing here?
沒人打，那我們怎麼會在這堙H
-Hold on. Where's Mike? -I just told you where Mike was.
等等，麥克呢？
You boys see all right?
你們看得到嗎？ 不是該…？
-Huh? You fucking smartass. -Listen. Listen.
-聽好！ -你這臭小子！
For our safety, for everyone's safety, we need to see your IDs.
為了安全起見，請出示身份證
Guys, hold up. We been here all morning, Take it easy.
等一下，我們整個上午 一直都在這堙A冷靜點
My partner asked for your ID. All right? We don't know you.
我的搭檔要你們出示身份證 我們不認識你們
Till we identify all the parties involved here, we're gonna need some IDs...
我門需要看你們的身份證
...we need to see everyone on the ground. Right now.
也要大家趴在地上，現在！
-Get your hand off your weapon. -Hey, relax.
不要掏槍
-Get on the ground! -Get on the fucking ground.
-趴下來！ -趴在地上！
Behind your back. Come on.
手放在背後，快點
Get your hands behind your back. Hands behind your back. Let's go.
手放在背後，快點！
-Take it easy. -Fuck.
-別激動 -去你的！
In the cash room.
現金室堛漱H
Arnold Washton. You live at 311 Hazer Street in Quincy...
阿諾·華許頓，海瑟街3 1 1號
...with a wife named Linda and three small dogs.
老婆叫琳達，家埵3只小狗
Do not make a distress call.
不准啟動警鈴
Also in the cash room:
現金室堛漱H還有
Morton Previtt. You live at 27 Counting Lane, Randolph.
莫頓·普瑞維特
Wife, also Linda.
老婆也叫琳達
Morton, the Lindas want you to open this door.
莫頓，這兩個琳達要你打開門
We have men outside your homes.
我們有手下守在你們家外面
Back up. Back up.
退後，退後
You think you're gonna get out of here?
你們別想逃得出去
I got friends that are guards at Walpole. They'll make your lives hell.
我朋友是獄卒，他們會整死你們
Well, don't you worry about it, old-timer.
別替我們擔心，沒人會坐牢
Ten more.
再來十個
Right away.
馬上
Picking up.
拿走
--least from the fan base when the Red Sox win.
紅襪隊贏球，球迷在瘋狂慶祝
When the Red Sox win in extra innings and everybody can go home happy...
紅襪隊贏了，球迷都開心得要命
...and they're singing 'Dirty Water"--
他們在唱《髒水》
-How you doing? -Fucking beautiful.
-怎麼樣？ -棒呆了
Come on.
快點
Last motherfucker who robbed the Red Sox like this was Jack Clark.
上一個搶紅襪隊錢的人是 傑克·克拉克
Looked around the block. There's no cars, no vans around. Nothing.
你看，一輛車也沒有，沒出事
Maybe we're too early. Or too late.
也許我們來得太早或太晚
Let's go. I want this street clear. Come on, get these people out of here. Let's go.
大夥兒，淨空這條街
We've been trying to hail security for the cash room. We're not getting a response.
長官，我們一直在聯絡現金室的警衛
Okay, let's go, Let's get the fuck out of here.
走吧，快閃吧
Come on.
快點
Shit.
可惡
-Fuck! -Let's get the fuck out of here!
-該死！ -快走！
That's us inside.
堶惘釵菑v人
Go! Go!
快！快！
Fuckers!
王八蛋！
Gloans! Gloans. Fuck.
葛隆！葛隆！可惡！
-He all right? -He's all right. They just got the vest.
-他沒事吧？ -沒事，只打到防彈背心
Yo, Dez, get the plunger!
戴斯！打開閘門！
Shut it!
關起來！
Dez?
戴斯！
Come on, come on.
快，快
They look like EMTs.
他們扮成急救人員
I count four. Maybe one down.
我算到四人，一人可能受傷
Go.
上吧
Let's get the fuck out of here.
趕快閃人吧！
There's a million fucking cops out there.
外面有一大堆警察
Dez!
德茲
Listen.
聽著
The three of us, even if we get out of here, we're getting the full ride, okay?
我們三個就算逃離了這 我們最終也會被抓回來
You walk out with your hands up, you could get seven years.
你把手舉起來走出去 你可能會被判七年
No one'll think the worse of you.
沒有人會看貶你
Fuck you.
去你的
Cover your ears!
摀住耳朵！
No!
不！
-All right, go, go, go. -All right, move it out.
-好了，上，上 -快，快
Fuck you!
去你的！
Move down. Get them the fuck out of here.
過去，把他們救出來
Meet me at the fucking switch!
到接應車那婺I頭
They ain't looking for fucking cops.
他們不會懷疑警察
I'm gonna roll out the front...
我從前面開車出去
...the two of youse beat it out the side in the fucking cop uniforms.
你們穿警察制服從旁邊逃走
The whole fucking force is out there, kid.
全部的警力都在外面
You know I can take a pinch.
我被逮沒關係
Don't worry about it. I'll only give them your first name.
放心，我不會招出你們
Clear.
安全！
Okay, go.
好，行動
Move, move.
快，快！
Hey, don't move. Don't move.
別動！別動！
-Put your weapons down. -Fuck you. Boston P.D.
-把槍放下！ -我們是波士頓警察
Look out, coming through. Stand down, Stand down.
小心！站住！站住！
See you in Florida, kid.
佛州見了
See you when you get back.
等你回來見
All right. Go.
好吧
All right, guys, let's back up. Feds got this.
大夥兒，我們退後！
Hey. Hey.
嘿…
You B.P.D. need to fuck off.
波士頓警察快滾！
What are you doing? It's an FBI crime scene.
這是FBI的犯罪現場
Don't put your hand up to me, Go.
別碰我，快滾！
Jurisdiction, guys. Walk away.
這是我們的案子，走開
That's my kill.
他是我射死的
I don't know if we're dealing with...
我不知道這堛瘧善穫O不是天才
...but security's saying they got hit by cops.
但他們說搶匪扮成警察
Cops?
警察？
Yeah. Two cops, they said.
對，兩個警察
Hold up.
等一下
Where you going?
你要去哪堙H
Pull up here.
靠邊停
Officer, can you hold up a minute?
警官，請爾站住
Visual on Coughlin, heading south toward Boylston.
考克林正往南逃逸
Hotel parking lot on Van Ness.
他在飯店停車場
He's dressed as B.P.D.
打扮成波士頓警察
Copy.
收到
Officer.
警官
Coughlin.
考克林
Drop your weapon!
放下武器！
No!
不！
Move! Move!
快、快！
Coughlin, throw down your weapon.
考克林！把槍丟掉！
Fuck you.
去你的
Let me see those hands, right now.
小詹，把手伸出來！
Move, move.
快，快！
You got 30 seconds, asshole.
你只有3 0秒，混蛋
Okay.
好吧
I surrender.
我投降！
Rusty, something went wrong.
洛帝，事情不對勁
Come here.
過來
Fergie.
付老大
Prick.
小雜種
Fergie...
付老大…
...remember who clipped your nuts for you.
記住是誰開槍閹了你
I came in hot, saw the suspect run across the street with a Tec-9.
我看到嫌犯持槍跑過去
I lit up the tires, I jumped out of the cruiser, engaged the suspect in gunfire.
於是馬上煞車，跳下警車 和嫌犯展開槍戰
So that's when...
你那時候跳下警車
At that point, I fired, struck the suspect at least once or twice.
然後我至少射到嫌犯兩槍
Hey.
嘿
Multiple victims down.
多名受害者死亡
Location, 529 Main Street, Charlestown.
地點是緬因街5 2 9號
-Uniformed officers on the scene. -That's the Florist.
-制服員警趕到現場 -是花店
Hey, Bobby, Bobby, what happened?
巴比，發生什麼事？
Somebody got Fergie.
有人殺死付老大
-Jesus Christ, that's gotta be MacRay. -Fuck.
-老天，一定是麥克雷 -可惡
Claire, it's me.
克萊爾，是我
Are you okay?
你沒事吧？
I'll be fine. I know.
沒事，我沒事
Claire, I wanna meet you.
克萊爾，我要見你
It's gotta be soon. I don't have a lot of time.
一定要快，我的時間不多
Can you meet me?
你能見我嗎？
Claire, please.
克萊爾，拜託
I need to know. I gotta go.
讓我知道，我得掛了
Can you come here?
你能過來嗎？
You want me to come where you are now?
你要我過去你那堙H
I don't think that's a good idea for me.
我不確定是好主意
Why?
為什麼？
What if there are police there?
要是有警察呢？
There's no one here.
這堥S有別人
All right, well, if you think I should probably come by there...
好吧，你要我過去我就過去
Okay.
好吧
Claire, listen, I'm-- Listen. Listen to me.
克萊爾，聽我說… 我…
I'm sorry, okay?
很抱歉，好嗎？
I'm sorry for what I did to you.
我為我對你做的事感到抱歉
Remember that.
請你記住
Come down in the back and let me in in about an hour:
一小時後到後門讓我進去
All right?
好嗎？
I'll see you.
到時候見
Wait, Doug? Doug?
等等，道格？
-Yeah. -I want you to come.
-是的 -我要你來，我真的很想見你
It'll be just like one of my sunny days.
這將會像是我的晴天
Well...
嗯…
...I'm on my way then.
我這就過去
Bye.
拜
Goodbye, Claire.
再見，克萊爾
All right, I'd say we've done our part here.
我們已經照你的要求做了
You know what? Not now.
現在別煩我
He says he's coming, I want people at Logan, South Station...
我知道他說要來
-The city's covered. -Good.
-全都要有人守 -很好
We 're secure, and everything 's ready.
我們已經戒備 都準備好了
-Sir, we need you to stay off the street. -Just going to work. No problem.
先生，請不要在街上走
-How long? -Forty minutes.
-多久了？ -4 0分鐘
-Alleyway clear? -Yes, sir.
-巷道淨空了嗎？ -淨空了
We got nothing. Still no movement in the alley. Over.
巷道沒有任何動靜
Well, I guess he didn't have as big a thing for you as you thought.
我想他送給你的禮物 沒你想像的那麼大份
I guess not.
我想是的
"My sunny days."
「我的晴天」
You know, Claire, we are a national organization.
你知道，克萊爾 我們是全國性的組織
All right, boys, let's pack it up. He ain't coming.
準備走人，他不會來了
Let's get the description out. Let's go.
發出追緝令，走吧
We know what he looks like.
我們知道他的長相
Let's go find him.
去找他吧
All right. You good?
好了，你沒事吧？
Hey, best possible outcome, you know.
這是最好的結果
Well done, well done.
做得好
It's for you.
這是給你的
Claire, take this.
克萊爾，把錢收下
You'll do better with it than I can.
你比我更會利用
By the time you read this, I'll be long gone.
當你看到紙條，我早已走遠
Not the way I planned it...
和我計劃的不一樣
...but for the first time in my life, I'm leaving this city.
但是我終於這輩子 第一次離開這城市
Maybe if I go...
也許我離開後
...I can stop looking.
就不會再找我媽了
No matter how much you change...
不管改變多少
You still have to pay the price for the things you've done.
人還是要為做過的事付出代價
So I got a long road.
我有很長的路要走
But I know I'll see you again.
但我知道我會再見到你
This side or the other.
今生或來世